米高梅影业　出品
片名：《夜阑人未静》（又译：柏油丛林）
约翰·休斯顿　制作作品
领衔主演：斯特林·海登、路易斯·卡尔亨
联袂主演：简·哈根、詹姆斯·惠特摩、山姆·谢斐
约翰·麦克因泰、马克·劳伦斯、巴里·凯利
剧本编写：本·马多　与　约翰·休斯顿
改编自　威廉·赖利·伯内特　所著小说
字幕来源：九区碟商ＹＪ译本（上传者：喷子＠ＳｕｂＨＤ）
修正校订：非傲慢即偏见＠ＳｕｂＨＤ
制片：小阿瑟·霍恩布洛
导演：约翰·休斯顿
３１Ｔ号警车，艾什顿公寓楼，三层
Car 3-1-T, Ashton Apartment Building. Third floor.
３１和３６号警车，福特街９２６号
Cars 3-1 and 3-6, 926 Ford Street.
３１和３６号警车，福特街９２６号，已有警员就位
Cars 31 and 36, 926 Ford Street. Officers going there now.
１９Ａ号警车…
Car 19-A...
Car 1-9-A...
请注意，７１号警车
Attention, Car 71.
持枪抢劫，巴黎旅馆，卡姆登广场南边
Holdup, Hotel de Paris, Camden Square South.
持枪抢劫，巴黎旅馆
Holdup, Hotel de Paris.
疑犯持有武器，白人男子，身材高大
Armed suspect -- tall man, Caucasian,
穿深色西服，戴呢帽
wearing a dark suit and soft hat.
这是７１号警车，收到
Car 71. Roger.
（咖啡、家味美食）
戈斯
Gus.
戈斯！这个混混什么时候进来的？
Gus! What time did this punk come in here?
别问我，我从不看钟，我拥有这家餐馆
Don't ask me. I don't watch the clock. I own the joint.
- 他没带枪　- 我要搜查这家餐馆
- No gun.  - I'll search the joint.
- 你有搜查令吗？　- 戈斯，你为什么不配合一下？
- You got a warrant?  - Now look, Gus, why don't you cooperate?
- 拿搜查令来　- 把他带走
- Get a warrant.  - Take him in.
- 什么理由？　- 把他按流浪汉登记
- On what?  - We'll book him on vag.
好吧，你跟我们走
All right, come on, you.
快点
Come on.
卡尔·安顿·史密斯，三十七岁
Smith, Karl Anton, age 37.
昨天傍晚六点被捕
Arrested 6:00 PM last night.
打电话给警局说他谋杀了凯瑟琳·史密斯夫人
Phoned police station stating he had murdered Mrs. Kathryn Smith.
威廉·杜迪，二十二岁
Doldy, William, age 22.
私藏毒品，职业是书记员，没有犯罪前科
Possession narcotics. Occupation, clerk. No previous record.
昨晚上吊自杀未遂
Attempt suicide last night with necktie.
威廉·塔特·汉德利，别名迪克斯·汉德利
Handley, William Tuttle, alias Dix Handley.
三十六岁，出生于肯塔基州
Age 36, born Kentucky.
无职业
Occupation, none.
一九三七年因非法持有枪械被捕，判五年以下有期徒刑
Arrested 1937, illegal possession firearms. Sentence, one to five.
一九三九年逃出州立监狱
Escaped state prison 1939.
于一九四〇年再次被捕，一九四一年释放
Arrested 1940, released 1941.
够了
That's enough.
你能认出昨晚抢劫的那个男人吗？
Well, do you see the man who pulled the stickup last night?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 你不知道是什么意思？　- 那个男人戴着帽子
- What do you mean, you don't know?  - He had a hat on.
把帽子都戴上
Put on your hats.
现在呢？
Well?
你说过那个男人很高，他穿着棕色西服，戴着宽沿帽
He was tall, you say. He had on a brown suit and a wide-brim hat.
你不是正看着他吗？
All right, don't you see him?
快点！是不是这个男人？
Well, come on! Is that him?
不，不是这个男人
No, it isn't him.
- 好吧　- 就这样
- Okay.  - That's all.
- 迪崔克警长？　- 什么事？
- Lieutenant Ditrich?  - What is it?
局长让你立即去他办公室
Commissioner wants to see you in his office right away.
坐下，警长
Sit down, Lieutenant.
谢谢，长官
Thank you, sir.
三十九起偷窃，三十三起入室盗窃，十八起抢劫
Thirty-nine thefts, 33 burglaries, 18 robberies,
七起人身侵犯，五起道德侵犯
seven assaults, five morals offenses
这仅仅是过去一个月内的案件
in the past 30 days.
即便是对第四警区来讲，这记录也太严重了
Quite a record, even for the Fourth Precinct, Lieutenant Ditrich.
局长，我们知道那个惯犯是谁
We know the guy who's been pulling most of the stickups, Commissioner.
他名叫迪克斯·汉德利，他今早被带来做疑犯辨认
Name's Dix Handley. He was in the show-up this morning,
但证人临阵退缩，没有指认他
but our witness got cold feet and backed down.
- 我们能怎么办？　- 把那个证人关起来！逼他说！
- What can you do?  - Lock up the witness! Scare him worse!
你应该知道如何做你的工作
It's your job knowing what to do.
在你的辖区内，唯一完好无损的店铺
As things are, the only merchants safe from harm in your precinct
是那些搞押注赌马的
are those who take wages on the horses.
我想知道那些场所怎么还在运转
I want to know why those parlors are still operating.
我关闭过它们，可它们又死灰复燃了
I close them down, but they only open up again.
你没有斩草除根！你得拔掉他们的电话线！砸烂家具！
You don't close 'em hard enough! Rip out the phones! Smash up the furniture!
长官，人们喜欢赌马，仅仅因为法律说不…
People like to bet the horses, sir, and just because the law says no --
轮不到你跟我谈法律
I don't want your opinion of the law.
- 长官，交代完了吗？　- 不，还没完
- Is that all, sir?  - No, that's not all.
厄文·瑞登施奈德在哪里？
Where is Erwin Riedenschneider?
- 我也在打听他，长官　- 你不知道他在哪里吗？
- I'm waiting to hear on that, sir.  - You don't know where he is, do you?
不知道，长官，但我们能从我们的线人那里得到消息
No, sir, but we ought to get word from our stoolies.
你得为此事全权负责
It was all dumped in your lap.
昨天中午十二点，他从州立监狱释放后乘火车来本市
He left state prison yesterday at 12 noon, took a train for this city.
到达时间是三点十七分
Time of arrival, 3:17.
你所要做的只是跟踪他，对他进行二十四小时监控
All you had to do was spot him, stay with him for 24 hours.
如果他没按规定登记，把他关起来
If he didn't register, lock him up.
可结果呢？他在火车站的五个街区外甩掉了你
But what happens? He loses you five blocks from the depot.
一个极其危险的罪犯正在本市逍遥法外
And one of the most dangerous criminals alive is now at large in this city.
跟踪他的两个警员应该为愚蠢失职获得「奖章」
The two men on that detail ought to get medals for dumbness.
是你派他们去的，你也应该获得「奖章」
They were assigned by you. You oughta get one too.
迪崔克，我能用三种方法惩罚你
Ditrich, I can do three things about you.
我能把你贬为巡警，送你到偏僻的街角
I can reduce you to patrolman and send you down to Five Corners,
我也能让内务部以玩忽职守的名义审判你
I can bring you up for departmental trial on charges of incompetence,
或者我还能再给你一次机会去履行你的职责
or I can give you one more chance to make good on your responsibilities.
我觉得最后一种方法是最好的惩罚
I think that'll be the greatest punishment of all.
谢谢，长官
Thank you, sir.
这就是你要找的门牌号
There's the number you're looking for.
但天已经黑了，你想让我等你吗？
But it's dark. You want me to wait?
我要是你就不会拎着提箱在这附近转悠
I wouldn't go parading around this neighborhood with a suitcase.
某些青年混混可能就为了一件干净衬衫打劫你
Some of these young punks might clip ya just to get a clean shirt.
- 什么事？　- 我找考比
- Yeah?  - I want to see Cobby.
- 你是谁？　- 就说博士来了，他想见考比
- Who are you?  - Just say Doc is here and would like to see him.
在这里等着，你最好有正当理由，哥们儿
Wait here. You'd better be on the legit, pal.
你有什么筹码？
What do you got?
三张三
Three threes.
他是何方鬼怪？
Well, where the devil is he?
有事快说，我很忙，你想做什么？
All right, make it fast. I'm a busy man. What do you want?
- 我今天刚出狱　- 噢，原来如此
- I just got out today.  - Oh, so that's it.
我厌倦了你们这种人找我要吃要喝，我又不是银行
I'm tired of you guys that fell putting the bite on me. I'm no First National Bank.
- 我有一份提议给你　- 你们这种人总有提议
- I got a proposition for you.  - All you guys have.
- 也许你还不知道我是谁　- 我从未见过你
- Maybe you didn't get who I was.  - I never seen you before.
- 快说，什么事？　- 也许你听说过我
- Come on, come on. What is it?  - Maybe you've heard of me.
听说过「教授」吗？也有人用德语叫我「博士先生」
The Professor? Or Herr Doktor, maybe.
你的意思是，你就是瑞登施奈德？
You mean, you are Riedenschneider?
你为什么不早说？
Well, why didn't you say so?
快进来，博士，快进来
Come on in, Doc. Come on in.
坐下，博士，坐下
Sit down, Doc. Sit down.
- 喝杯酒吗？　- 不必
- Have a drink?  - Nothing to drink.
我坐牢时把喝酒的喜好戒掉了
I got out of the habit behind the walls.
- 戒掉喝酒这喜好很容易　- 那我就为喝酒这喜好干一杯
- That's all it is -- a habit.  - Well, here's to the drink habit.
这是唯一不会给我带来麻烦的喜好
It's the only one I got that don't get me into trouble.
言归正传，博士，你有什么想法？
Well, Doc, what's on your mind?
我有一份提议，很大的提议
I got a proposition. A big one.
- 很大是多大？　- 这提议对你而言太大了，考比
- How big is big?  - Too big for you, Cobby.
博士，我不喜欢吹牛，但我也混得不错
Now, wait, Doc. I don't like to brag, but I'm doing all right.
我从事赌注登记，我有赢钱筹码
Makin' book. I'm in the chips.
- 到底是什么提议？　- 一起盗窃计划
- What kind of proposition is it?  - A plan for a caper.
绝好的生意，我可以在公开市场把货物卖十万美元
And it's a good one. I could sell it for $100,000 on the open market,
但那样做不值得，相当于把钱扔掉
but that would be throwing money away.
我更喜欢亲自处理货物…
I prefer to execute it myself and make --
- 能赚多少？　- 五十万美元
- How much?  - Half a million dollars.
也许更多
Maybe even more.
当然，我会事先做些准备工作，毕竟这计划搁置了好几年
Of course I will have to do a little checking, as the plan is some years old.
但准备工作要的钱不多，不多
But not much checking. Not much.
我需要大概五万块钱的经费
I need roughly 50,000 to operate.
五万块钱？
Fifty thousand?
不行，我看不行
No, no, no, I don't see.
当然，我想埃默瑞克先生也许能帮忙
Of course. I thought maybe Mr. Emmerich.
你还知道埃默瑞克先生？
What do you know about Mr. Emmerich?
我只是坐牢时有所耳闻
Only what I heard in the walls --
他有钱投资，而通过你可以找到他
that he has money to invest and that the way to get to him is through you.
除非我的情报不正确…
Of course, if my information is not correct...
当然正确，完全正确
Correct. Sure. Sure, it's correct.
我只是没想到埃默瑞克先生也会和此类交易扯上关联
It's just that I never thought of Mr. Emmerich in connection with this kind of a deal.
失陪一会儿，我马上回来
Excuse me a minute. I'll be right back.
喂？
Hello?
谢谢，稍后见
Thanks. See ya later.
你好，迪克斯，你想要什么？
Hello, Dix. What do you want?
- 我想来押注　- 噢？
- I wanna make a bet.  - Well?
- 你的人说得先经你同意　- 你要押注多少？
- Your man says you got to okay it.  - What are you in for?
大概两千三百块钱
2,300 and some.
好的，你可以赊账押注两千五百块钱
Okay. Your tab's good for 2,500.
但那是上限，你要么押个赢家赚钱，要么输光后还我钱
But that's the limit. Either pick a winner or pay me when you get that far.
不要挖苦我！
Don't bone me!
- 我没有挖苦…　- 我赖账过吗？
- Now, look, I'm not boning --  - Did I ever welsh?
- 没人说你赖账　- 你刚才挖苦我
- Nobody said you did.  - You just boned me.
- 迪克斯…　- 我不需要你的人情
- Look, Dix --  - I'm not asking you any favors.
我现在就去给你拿两千三百块钱
I'll go get you your 2,300 right now.
别走，迪克斯，你要喝杯酒吗？来吧
Now, Dix. Now, Dix, listen. Will you have a drink? Come on.
迪克斯，回来喝杯酒吧
Dix, come back here. Have a drink.
岂有此理！
Can you beat that?
- 他的脾气为什么总这样火爆？　- 他是谁？
- Where does he come off blowing a fuse?  - Who is he?
一个不入流的恶棍，赌马赌疯了
A small-time hooligan who's crazy for horses.
他一直来我这里押注赌马，却总是输
My book beats him and beats him, he keeps coming back for more.
瞧，博士
Say, Doc.
我都忘记那笔大买卖了
I forgot on account of that big tramp.
我在电话里跟埃默瑞克先生说了，他今晚稍后会见我们
I spoke to Mr. Emmerich on the phone. He's gonna meet us later on tonight.
他正在他市区的房子里为富翁们举办晚宴
He's giving a dinner party at his house in town for a bunch of swells,
但他稍后会在他另一处房子见我们
but he'll be at another address later on.
像埃默瑞克这种人总是有不止一处房子用来歇脚
A man like Emmerich has got more than one place to hang his hat.
聪明的猫咪，从不干活，晚上出门，白天睡觉
Smart cat. Never does a lick of work, stays out all night, sleeps all day.
把又肥又脏的猫带进餐馆来干嘛？
What's a big, dirty cat doing at an eating joint?
我每次开车碰到猫都会碾压过去
I run over one every time I get a chance.
有人喂猫，而有些孩子却吃不饱饭
People feeding cats, and some kids haven't got enough to eat.
你到底买不买那本杂志？
You gonna buy that magazine?
为什么要买？我只看美女插图，已经看完了
Why should I? I seen all the dames in it already.
你对此想怎样？
Wanna make something of it?
浑球，你是不是有点过分？
You're a little off your beat, ain't you, buster?
矮驼子，你什么意思？
How do you mean, Humpty Dumpty?
我的意思是你不属于这里，你只是路过的
I mean, you don't belong around here. You're just passing through.
赶紧滚吧
Only not fast enough.
如果我真看到你碾压猫咪，我会把你打得满地找牙
If I ever see you running over a cat, I'll kick your teeth out.
如果你再长高点，也不驼背，我早就把你撕碎了
I'd take you apart if you were about a foot taller and straightened up a little.
我猜你是想拿回你的武器
Suppose you want your heater back.
我不会给你的，你打算把我怎样？
Well, you ain't gonna get it. What do you think of that?
- 戈斯，别开玩笑　- 我认真的
- Quit kidding, Gus.  - I mean it.
发火呀，把我打倒去拿枪
Go on, get sore. Smack me down.
你知道我不会那么做的
You know I wouldn't do that.
迪克斯，听我的建议，先休息一段时间
Look, Dix, take my advice and knock off for a while.
那些警察小子在疯狂抓人，总部把他们逼得很紧
The happiness boys are on a rampage. Headquarters has given them the push.
- 我负担不起休息　- 别担心，我会借钱给你
- I can't afford to knock off.  - Oh, stop worrying. I'll stake you.
- 是吗？可我需要两千三百块钱　- 什么？
- Yeah? I need 2,300.  - What?
- 我有事要急用　- 找过考比吗？
- Something I just gotta take care of.  - Cobby, maybe?
让考比为此出汗吧，这对他有好处，他能拿出一些钱
Well, let him sweat. It'll do him good. Cobby can spare a few pounds.
你不能给他那种人欠钱
You can't owe money to a guy like him,
那个满嘴铜臭味的小人只会挖苦你
a little loudmouth who bones you when he isn't even trying to.
迪克斯，我没听懂
I don't get you, Dix.
我不想再给考比欠债，我想留点自尊
I just can't be in Cobby's debt and keep my self-respect.
噢
Oh.
好吧
All right.
我手头上有一千块钱，你可以借去用
I got a grand put away. You can have that.
我再想办法弄另外一千三百块钱
Maybe I can dig up 1,300 more.
- 我猜你欠我的钱就没问题，是吧？　- 我猜是的
- I guess it's all right to owe me, huh?  - I guess.
那我可真荣幸
Yeah. It's just my luck.
我尽量明天弄到钱
Well, I'll get it tomorrow or bust a gut.
与此同时，你别在街道上转悠，尤其是晚上
In the meantime, stay away from the boulevard, especially at night.
另外，警察抄封了那家高档会所，雷格尔俱乐部
By the way, they knocked over that clip joint, the Club Regal.
- 朵儿不是在那里工作吗？　- 是的
- Wasn't that where Doll worked?  - Yeah.
- 好像来了大批警察　- 是的
- It's coming in bunches, it looks like.  - Yeah.
迪克斯，回家老实待着
Go home, Dix. Stay home.
好吧
Yeah.
别垂头丧气的，记住，你仍有老戈斯当后盾
Don't get your flag at half-mast. Remember, you still got old Gus.
一千三百块钱？你疯了吧
Thirteen hundred? You must be crazy.
为了迪克斯？我干嘛关心那个恶棍？
For Dix? What do I care for that hooligan?
戈斯，我也想帮你
I'd like to help you out, Gus,
但我要养家糊口，还得交房租之类的
but I got mouths to feed and rent to pay and all that stuff.
你这肥大的意大利佬…道友，你怎么不机灵点？
You great big, fat Italian -- Why don't you wise up, you wise guy?
- 你是个人渣　- 安静！
- You're a low-down scum.  - Shh!
你这人渣竟敢这么跟我说话
A low-down, dirty scum to talk to me like that.
戈斯，听着
Look, Gus.
我猜我可以帮忙
I guess I can make it, all right.
- 谁啊？　- 迪克斯，是我，朵儿
- Yeah?  - Dix, it's me, Doll.
朵儿？
Doll?
嗨，亲爱的
Hi, honey.
进来吧
Come on in.
- 关上门　- 当然，迪克斯
- Close the door.  - Well, sure, Dix. Sure.
亲爱的，我很抱歉打搅你，但是…
I'm awful sorry to bother you, honey, but...
朵儿，如果妳想抽烟，记得带火柴
Doll, if you're gonna smoke, you gotta learn to carry matches.
朵儿，妳哭什么？
Doll, what are you crying about?
没什么，迪克斯，没什么
N-Nothin', Dix. Nothing.
对不起
I'm sorry.
迪克斯，对不起
I'm sorry, Dix.
这么晚还来打搅你，我也不知道我在想什么
I don't know what I was thinking about, bothering you at this time of the night.
我这就走
I'll just run along.
戈斯跟我说雷格尔俱乐部被抄封了
Gus told me the Club Regal got knocked over.
是的，雷格尔竟然被抄封，你能想象吗？
Yeah. Can you imagine, raiding the Regal?
那些警察一定是疯了
The cops must have all gone crazy.
即便是高档会所又怎样？
So it's a clip joint. So what?
而且警察正好在发薪日来抄封
And it would have to happen on pay night.
- 想喝杯酒吗？　- 我不介意来一杯
- How about a drink?  - Hey, I don't care if I do.
我的一个假睫毛掉了
One of my eyelashes is coming off.
妳被房东赶出门了吗？
Were you, uh, locked out of your room?
你怎么猜到的？
How'd you guess?
呃…为倒霉日干杯
Well... here's how.
迪克斯，如果不太麻烦的话，我能在你这里待几天吗？
Uh, Dix, if it wouldn't be too much trouble, could I stay here a couple of days?
就一、两天
Just a day or two.
好吧，朵儿，妳可以待在这里，但妳不要有别的想法
All right. Stay if you want to. But don't you go getting any ideas, Doll.
一切都已计划周密，从轮流值班看守
Everything is here, from the observed routine of the personnel
到警报系统，门锁的型号
to the alarm system, the type of locks on doors,
还有主保险柜的使用年数及其它信息
the age and condition of the main safe and so forth and so forth.
埃默瑞克先生，相信我，现在是「万事俱备，只欠东风」
Take my word for it, Mr. Emmerich. This is a ripe plum ready to fall.
朋友，所有江湖人士都说是「小事一桩」
My friend, according to the boys, all takes are easy.
但作为律师，我却以帮助他们洗脱罪名赚大钱
But as a lawyer, I've made a lot of money getting them out of jail.
埃默瑞克先生，也许你知道我的名声
Please, Mr. Emmerich. Perhaps you know my reputation.
我策划过不少大买卖
I've engineered some very big things.
埃默瑞克先生，确实如此，博士是顶尖高手
That's a fact, Mr. Emmerich. Doc here is tops.
据我所知，你本来是为了上次行动而搜集的这些信息？
Am I to understand you gathered this information before doing your last stretch?
没错，我原本已经准备动手
That is correct. I was ready to begin operations,
然后因为一宗我几乎忘记的陈年盗窃案，臭警察把我抓了
and the coppers grabbed me for an old caper I'd almost forgotten about.
阿德菲亚金融公司盗窃案
The Adelphia Finance caper.
博士从中赚了十六万美元，对吗？
You took 'em for 160,000, didn't you, Doc?
十五万八千美元
A hundred and fifty-eight.
你真觉得这笔买卖可以按百万美元计算吗？
And you really believe there's a million in this thing?
也许更多
Maybe even more.
你的意思是干这一票就可以赚五十万美元现金吗？
You mean by that that the take will be worth half a million to us in actual cash?
但你我都知道
Because you know as well as I do
销赃者最多只会给五成价
that in no case will a fence give you more than 50 percent.
没错
That's right, sir.
- 那你的主要问题是什么？　- 有三项难题
- Well, what are your main problems?  - There are three.
行动经费，帮手
Money to operate, personnel,
最后是，货物如何出手
and finally, the disposing of the take.
埃默瑞克先生，第一项没问题，对吧？
No trouble about the first, eh, Mr. Emmerich?
且慢，考比，情况还有待观察
Wait a minute, Cobby. This remains to be seen.
帮手们只会领取固定报酬
The helpers will be paid off like house painters.
我不会告诉他们这笔买卖有多大
They'll be told nothing about the size of the take.
人有时会变得太贪婪
Sometimes men get greedy.
- 那你需要多少帮手？　- 只需三个
- Well, how many helpers do you need?  - Only three.
一个开锁专家
A box man.
付给他的报酬最多，大概两万五千美元
Him, we pay most. Maybe $25,000.
我想到个人，路易·查维利，芝加哥西区最好的开锁匠
I got a guy for you. Louis Ciavelli. Best box man west of Chicago.
机械锁专家，曾干过一些大型盗窃案
Expert mechanic. Been in some very big capers.
我听说他开保险柜跟拆表一样轻松，但他要价很高
From what I hear, he can open a safe like the back of a watch. Only, he costs.
然后我们需要一个顶级车手，以防逃跑时用到他
Then we need a top-notch driver, in case of a rumble.
- 车手只用付一万块钱　- 嗯哼
- He should get 10,000.  - Mm-hmm.
最后，不得不说，我们需要一个恶棍
Finally, sad to say, we need a hooligan.
这种人大多数有毒瘾，他们毫无优点
Most of these fellas are drug addicts. They're a no-good lot.
他们只知道使用暴力，但遗憾的是此类行动需要恶棍
Violence is all they know, but they are, unfortunately, necessary.
如果这恶棍可靠的话，我会付给他一万五千块钱
For a more or less reliable man, I'd say 15,000.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
那总共是五万块钱
Well, that's 50,000 in all.
如何…
How, uh --
如何把赃物卖出去？
How's this take to be handled?
联系中西部最好的销赃者们
We'll get in touch with the best fences in the Midwest
把赃物卖给出价最高的人
and deal with whoever makes the highest offer.
也许一个销赃者没那么多钱
Maybe no one fence can handle the whole thing.
那样的话，我们卖给两、三个销赃者
In that case, we deal with two or three.
五十万美元，是吧？
Half a million, eh?
我…
I, uh...
我…我在想
I'm, uh... I'm just thinking.
如果我决定参与，我…
If I decide to go into this thing, I, uh...
我自己可以买下这些…
I, myself, I might handle the...
埃默瑞克先生，你做销赃者？
You, a fence, Mr. Emmerich?
不，考比，不完全是
Oh, no, no, Cobby. Not exactly.
但这笔生意听起来很棒，我想卖它个最高价
But your proposition looks pretty good. I'd like to see the most made of it.
我猜人应该只做自己擅长的事
Oh, I suppose a fella should stick to his own trade,
但我也认识本地的一些大人物
but, uh, I know some pretty big men around here
如果沟通得当，他们也许会接受这样的交易
that might not be averse to a deal like this, if they're properly approached.
我补充一句，他们是非常受敬仰的大人物
Highly respectable men, I might add.
所以在你寻找销赃者之前，我先帮你问问情况，如何？
So why don't you let me see what I can do before you look for a fence, hmm?
就几天时间，我猜对你来说也没什么损失
A few days, more or less, wouldn't make much difference to you, I don't suppose.
- 如果成功，大家一起多赚钱　- 好的
- Might mean a lot more money for all of us.  - Good.
还有一件事，我不愿提起
There's just one thing. I dislike to mention it,
- 但我刚从监狱出来…　- 噢，当然
- but I've just come from prison and...  - Oh. Well, of course.
考比会给你安排住处，以及你需要的一切
Cobby will advance you anything you need, see that you have a place to stay.
- 考比，对吗？　- 那是当然
- Eh, Cobby?  - Well, you bet your life.
而且我还有一些特殊服务电话，博士
And I got some fancy phone numbers for you too, Doc.
像你这种有品味的人坐牢七年是什么滋味？
What's it like, a man of your taste, seven years behind the walls?
不算太糟，监狱可以磨炼性情
Not too bad. It's a matter of temperament.
我在里面不找麻烦，狱警喜欢犯人这样
I cause no trouble. The prison authorities appreciate that.
然后他们就让我做图书管理员
They made me assistant librarian.
恐怕我可当不了这种模范犯人
I'm afraid I wouldn't make a model prisoner.
干完这一票，我就到墨西哥，去过国王般的日子
After this job, it's Mexico for me. I'll live like a king.
墨西哥女孩非常漂亮
Mexican girls are very pretty.
我每天什么也不做，就在阳光下追求她们
I'll have nothing to do all day long but chase them in the sunshine.
- 你非常大方，先生　- 晚安
- You've been very kind, sir.  - Good night. Good night.
- 再见，埃默瑞克先生　- 再见，考比
- Mr. Emmerich.  - Cobby.
朗大叔，你站在那里盯着我干嘛？
What's the big idea, standing there staring at me, Uncle Lon?
别叫我「朗大叔」
Don't call me "Uncle Lon."
我还以为你喜欢呢
I thought you liked it.
也许我曾经喜欢
Maybe I did.
但现在不了
I don't anymore.
我让卖场给你送些咸水鲭鱼
I had the market send over some salt mackerel for you.
我知道你喜欢把它当早餐
I know how you love it for breakfast.
甜美的女孩
Some sweet kid.
很晚了
It's late.
妳为什么不去睡觉呢？
Why don't you go to bed?
甜美的女孩
Some sweet kid.
喂，是鲍勃·布兰姆吗？我是埃默瑞克
Hello, Bob Brannom? This is Emmerich.
不，我不是打电话聊天的
No, no. I didn't call you to get the right time.
听着，我有份工作交给你
Listen, I've got a job for you.
不，不是那种事
No, no. Nothing like that.
我有十万美元欠债没到帐
I've got over $100,000 standing out on my books.
明早到我办公室，我把欠债者的名单给你
Come to my office tomorrow morning, I'll give you a list of people that owe me.
不，不
No, no, no, no.
一个一个的想办法
Use the method called for in each particular case.
别跟我说任何过程，我只要结果
And don't tell me anything about it. All I want is results.
那又怎样？
So what?
放松，孩子，放松
Easy, boy. Easy.
喂
Hello.
你是谁？
Who?
噢，是戈斯呀
Oh, sure, Gus.
他还没睡醒
He's still asleep.
什么？
What?
好的，我会转告他
Yeah. Yeah, I'll tell him.
亲爱的，戈斯打来电话
Honey. Honey, that was Gus.
他说你随时可以去找他，他有东西给你
He says you can come over anytime. He's got something for you.
好的
Okay.
亲爱的，喝咖啡吗？我刚弄的
Coffee, honey? I made it fresh.
好的
Yeah. Yeah.
嘿，你肯定做梦了
Hey, you sure were dreaming.
- 妳怎么知道？　- 你睡着时还说话
- How do you know?  - You were talking in your sleep.
- 我说什么了？　- 都是些零散的话
- What was I saying?  - It was all jumbled up.
但有一个词语我听得很清楚，你说了好几次
But I heard one word real plain. You called it out several times.
「玉米饼干」
"Corn cracker."
那是什么意思？
What's that mean?
玉米饼干？
Corn Cracker?
玉米饼干是一匹雄马驹
Corn Cracker was a colt.
是这样啊
Yeah, it would be.
它是一匹高大的黑色雄马驹
Yeah. He was a tall, black colt.
我想起我做的梦了
Yeah, I remember what I was dreaming.
我骑在那匹雄马驹背上
I was up on that colt's back.
我父亲和我爷爷在旁边看着我取乐
My father and my grandfather were there, watching the fun.
那匹雄马驹正在跳跃、蹬蹄
That colt was buck-jumping and pitching.
它试图把我甩脱在篱笆上，但我还是骑着它
Once he tried to scrape me off against the fence, but I stayed with him, you bet.
然后我听到我爷爷说：
Then I heard my granddaddy say,
「他是汉德利家的棒小伙，正宗男子汉」
"He's a real Handley, that boy. A real Handley."
我当时骄傲极了
And I felt proud as you please.
迪克斯，那是真事吗？在你小时候？
Did that really happen, Dix, when you were a kid?
不完全是，那匹黑色雄马驹首次跳跃就把我甩脱在篱笆上
Not exactly. The black colt pitched me into a fence on the first buck.
然后我老爸走过来，用他的靴子踢着我说：
My old man come over, prodded me with his boot and said,
「也许这能教会你不要吹嘘自己擅长骑马」
"Maybe that'll teach you not to brag about how good you are on a horse."
很高兴看到你笑了
It's nice to hear you laugh.
妳知道吗？
You know something?
是我的祖辈首先把爱尔兰良种马引进县里的
One of my ancestors imported the first Irish thoroughbred into our county.
- 真的吗？　- 当然
- Is that a fact?  - Sure.
我们家的农场世代相传
Why, our farm was in the family for generations.
总共一百六十英亩的农场
One hundred sixty acres.
有三十英亩的广阔草地，其余的种庄稼
Thirty in bluegrass and the rest in crops.
漂亮谷仓，七匹母马
Fine barn and seven brood mares.
- 迪克斯，听起来真好　- 本来是的
- Sounds wonderful, Dix.  - It was.
然后一切发生得太突然
And then everything happened at once.
我老爸死了，我们的玉米田没了
My old man died, and we lost our corn crop.
那匹黑色雄马驹摔断了腿，我们只能射死它
That black colt I was telling you about, he broke his leg and had to be shot.
那是苦涩的一年
That was a rotten year.
我永远忘不了我们离开的那天
I'll never forget the day we left.
我和我弟弟发誓，总有一天我们要把山核桃木农场买回来
Me and my brother swore we'd buy Hickorywood Farm back someday.
被迫离开从小长大的地方一定很糟糕
Growing up in a place and then having to leave must be awful.
我从未有过一个像样的家
I never had a proper home.
一万两千块钱就能买回来，有一次我几乎做到了
Twelve grand would have swung it, and I almost made it once.
我手里有超过五千美元
I had more than $5,000 in my pocket
潘彭这匹马要参加比赛
and Pampoon was running in the Suburban.
我觉得这匹马不会输，我把所有钱都押给它
I figured he couldn't lose. I put it all on his nose.
它却输了
He lost by a nose.
亲爱的，喝咖啡吧，免得凉了
Drink your coffee, honey, before it gets cold.
我觉得我就要时来运转了
The way I figure, my luck's just gotta turn.
再过几天，我要干件大事，然后我就回老家
One of these days, I'll make a real killing. Then I'm gonna head for home.
回老家后我首先去溪流中洗澡，把这座城市的污垢都洗掉
First thing when I get there, I take a bath in the creek and get this city dirt off me.
- 怎么了？　- 没事，迪克斯，没事
- What's the matter?  - Nothing, Dix. Nothing. Nothing.
- 我说错什么了吗？　- 没有
- I say something wrong?  - No.
这地方一团糟，它需要好好清扫
But, gee, this place is a mess. It needs a good cleaning.
你怎么受得了如此生活？
How can you stand to live like this?
数数
Count it.
迪克斯，你不用一次性把赌注付清
Look, Dix. You don't have to pay the whole tab at once.
全数数看
Go ahead and count it.
干嘛生气？没必要生气
Why get sore? There's no reason to get sore.
你在陌生人面前挖苦我，试图贬低我
You boned me in front of a stranger, trying to make me look small.
我不是故意的，我这张嘴总说胡话，也许我喝醉了
I didn't mean it. I shoot my mouth off. Maybe I had a slight load on.
- 你知道怎么回事　- 不，我不这么认为
- You know how it is.  - No. No, I don't know how it is.
迪克斯
Look, Dix.
我犯了个错误，难道你从不犯错吗？
I made a mistake. Don't you ever make a mistake?
是吧
Sure. Sure.
来，喝杯酒
Here, have a drink.
来吧
Here you are.
迪克斯，给你
There you are, Dix.
迪克斯，赌马要放聪明点
You know, Dix, you gotta play the horses the smart way.
省着用钱，下次有内部消息我会告诉你
Save your money. The next time there's a fix going, I'll let you know.
稳赚不赔，稳赚不赔
It'll be money from home. Money from home.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
噢，是博士啊，快进来
Oh, it's the Doc. Come on in, Doc.
来见见我的朋友，迪克斯·汉德利
Want you to meet a friend of mine. Dix Handley.
这位是瑞登施奈德博士
This is Doc Riedenschneider.
- 你听说过他，对吧？　- 是的
- You heard of him, I guess, huh?  - Yeah.
你觉得威士忌如何？从你家乡产的
Well, how'd you like the whiskey? Made in your home state.
噢，你家乡在哪里？
Oh. Where is that, sir?
肯塔基州，布恩县
Kentucky. Boone County, Kentucky.
- 有美国最好的淡水　- 是吗？
- Best water in the USA.  - Is that so?
是的，那里的水让威士忌更可口
Yeah, it's the water makes the whiskey fit to drink.
好了…
Well...
我得走了，有机会再见
I gotta be going. I'll see you around sometime maybe.
再见，迪克斯
So long, Dix.
乡巴佬
Big hick.
他的钱很好赚，但他的脾气太敏感
The color of his money's all right, but I wish he wasn't so touchy.
也许这就是他令人尊敬的品质，会对赌债负责
Maybe it's a point of honor with him. A gambling debt.
他那恶棍令人尊敬？别让我笑掉大牙
Him? That hooligan? Honor? Don't make me laugh.
- 你说他是个恶棍？　- 对，但是不入流
- He's a hooligan, you say?  - Yeah, but a small-timer.
他只是抢劫香烟店、加油站，然后把所有钱拿去赌马
He'll stick up cigar stores, gas stations. And every cent goes to the ponies.
无论如何，我们都有自己的恶习
One way or another, we all work for our vice.
博士，你也有恶习吧？你昨晚的约会如何？
What do you say, Doc? How was your date last night?
那个年轻女士喝得大醉，算不上好伴侣
The young lady drank too much to be good company.
但夜晚并未完全浪费，她说的话比她清醒时更多
But the evening wasn't a complete loss. She talked more than if she'd been sober.
- 她说了什么？　- 你的朋友埃默瑞克先生
- Yeah? What about?  - Your friend Mr. Emmerich.
埃默瑞克？听着，博士
Emmerich? Now, look here, Doc.
这是笔五十万美元的大买卖，我得了解一切情况
There's half a million at stake. I've got to know where I stand.
埃默瑞克出资我才能雇佣帮手
Emmerich must put up before I can hire a crew.
对他而言，这是小菜一碟
For him, it's nothing. A dead cinch.
可昨晚的女士给我的信息是埃默瑞克破产了
The information she gave me is that he's broke.
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
我跟埃默瑞克先生打交道二十年了，他只接手大案子
I've seen Mr. Emmerich operate for 20 years. He handles only the biggest cases.
他有两栋房子，四辆车，半打佣人
He's got two houses, four cars, a half a dozen servants.
- 还包养了一个金发美女　- 博士！
- And one blond.  - Doc!
你相信谁的话？我的还是那个愚蠢小妞的？
Whose word you gonna take? Mine or some dim-witted dame?
当然相信你的
Yours, naturally.
如果他破产了，那我也想要像他那样破产
If he's broke, I wanna be broke the same way.
警长！警长！
Lieutenant! Lieutenant!
你在我办公室看见的那个人，他只是路过
That guy you saw in my office, he's just passing through.
闭嘴，我没看见任何人，我怎么可能？我没来过这里
Shut up. I didn't see anybody. How could I? I wasn't here.
对，是…是这样的
Yeah, that -- that's right. That's right.
- 听着…　- 什么事？
- Look, uh...  - Yeah?
我只是来通知你，你这里会有一次突击搜捕
I just came to tell you that, uh, you'll have to stand still for a raid.
你的意思是要拉我去警局里审讯？
You mean you have to haul me downtown and book me?
- 去警局的路程很短　- 我以为你是我的朋友！
- It's a short ride.  - I thought you were a friend of mine!
现在我迪崔克唯一的朋友是我自己
Right now I've got one friend -- Ditrich.
如果我迪崔克不做些抓捕行动，我就自身难保
And Ditrich's going to be out on his ear if he don't make a showing.
- 但为什么是我？为什么抓我？　- 因为这才符合常理
- All right, but why me? Why pick on me?  - Because it's logic.
你的赌注登记场所是我辖区内最大的
You're the biggest parlor in my precinct.
市民们知道，报社们知道，连我也知道
The citizens know it, the newspapers know it, and even I know it.
警察局长也知道我知道
And that Mr. Commissioner knows I know it.
我只是讨厌所发生的事
I just hate to have it happen. I just hate it, that's all.
- 我也很抱歉　- 警长，听着
- I'm as sorry as you are.  - Look, Lieutenant.
我已经跟你合作这么久了
I've always given you plenty of cooperation.
但现在抓我真的不是时候
But you're hitting me at just the wrong time.
那好吧
Well, all right.
关紧门
Close up tight.
不要开灯，不要接任何电话
Keep the place dark. Don't answer any phones.
多谢了，警长
Thanks, Lieutenant.
多谢了
Thanks.
那个臭警察认出我了
That copper, he recognized me.
- 你怎么知道他是臭警察？　- 我离一街区就能闻出来
- How'd you know he was a copper?  - I can smell one a block off.
别担心迪崔克，他收了我的黑钱，算是合伙人
Don't worry about Ditrich. He's on my payroll. Practically a partner.
我和他是一根绳上的蚂蚱
Me and him, we're like that.
经验教导我永远别相信警察
Experience has taught me never to trust a policeman.
当你觉得他靠得住时，他就会背后捅刀
Just when you think one's all right, he turns legit.
- 布兰姆先生来了　- 对，让他进来
- A Mr. Brannom is here.  - Oh, yes, show him in.
先生，还有件事，埃默瑞克夫人身体不舒服
Pardon me, sir. Mrs. Emmerich is not feeling well.
知道了，通知豪斯曼医生来
Yes, well, send for Dr. Houseman.
- 我已经通知了，先生　- 很好
- I already have, sir.  - Good.
告诉我太太…
Tell her I, uh...
说我稍后上楼见她
Say I'll be up to see her later.
我的欠债者们如何？有多少人还钱？
Well, what about my debtors? How many of them came through?
- 没有一个　- 什么？
- Not a one.  - What's that?
你想知道所有的借口吗？有些借口很精彩
You want all the excuses? I've got some beauts.
情况那么糟糕？
As bad as that, eh?
有两、三个人会还一部分钱，他们保证了
Two or three may come through with a part. They promised.
我不要保证，我只要现钱
I don't want promises. I want cash.
朋友，听着，私家侦探不能威胁人
Look, my friend, a private detective can't go around threatening people.
否则我会失去执照
I'd lose my license.
九成八的人你只能起诉他们
Ninety-eight percent of them you're gonna have to sue.
没有时间了，我…
There's no time for that. I...
我需要钱，我现在就需要钱
I gotta have money. I gotta have it this minute.
怎么回事？因为你那个金发女孩？
What is it? Girl trouble?
布兰姆，闭嘴！这不好笑
Shut up, Brannom! That's not funny.
什么？没人敢叫我闭嘴
How's that? Nobody tells me to shut up.
鲍勃，对不起
I'm sorry, Bob.
鲍勃，我…
Bob, I...
我破产了
I'm broke.
这是个简单明了的事实
There. Th-That's the plain, simple fact.
我完蛋了，我倒闭了
I'm finished. I'm bankrupt.
你怎么会让安吉拉这种女人把你整到破产？
How could you let a dame like Angela take you this way?
不是安吉拉的错，是这一切，是我的奢侈生活造成的
It's not Angela. It's everything. It's my whole way of life.
我每次开销都要花费数千美元
Every time I turn around, it costs thousands of dollars --
这里花一万美元，那里花一万美元
10,000 here, 10,000 there.
我必须…我必须脱身
I got... I gotta get out.
我必须彻底脱身
I gotta get out from under.
讽刺的是我现在有个机遇，但我却抓不住
And the irony of it is that I've got an opportunity and I can't take it.
很艰难
Tough.
鲍勃
Bob.
我会让你大吃一惊
I'm gonna hand you the shock of a lifetime.
你听说过瑞登施奈德博士吗？
Did you ever hear of Doc Riedenschneider?
当然，他不是在坐牢吗？
Sure. Behind the walls, isn't he?
不，他上周出狱了，考比带他来找我
No, he's out. He got out last week. Cobby brought him to me.
他有个计划，设计得非常完美
He's got a plan, beautifully worked out,
会是中西部有史以来最大的盗窃案
for the biggest caper ever to be pulled in the Middle West.
但他需要五万美元的经费
Only he wants $50,000 backing.
目标是谁？
Who would be taken?
贝拉提尔珠宝店
Belletier's.
保守地说，仅宝石就价值五十万美元
The rocks alone would be worth, conservatively speaking, half a million.
- 你能拿多少？　- 三分之一
- How much would you get out of it?  - A third of the take.
老兄，你真吓我一跳
Brother. You're knocking me out.
那如果我跟你说，我有个计划可以让我独吞一切呢？
What if I were to tell you that I've got a plan worked out to get it all?
我告诉他们让我来做销赃者，懂吗？
I could tell them that I'd fence the stuff myself, you see?
答应他们货物一到就付现金
Promise them cash on delivery.
然后…
Then...
等到交货时，我就说现金还没筹到，你明白吗？
when the time comes, I simply wouldn't have the cash. You understand?
我告诉他们筹钱还得几天
I'd tell them it'd take a few days more to raise it.
我确定能让他们在等钱时把货物放在我这里
I'm certain I could get them to leave the stuff with me while we're waiting.
- 继续说　- 然后我就消失
- Go on.  - Well, then I'd disappear.
坐飞机去别的国家，开始新生活
I'd take a plane to another country, to another life.
我可以把黄金和铂金融化成金条卖
The gold and platinum I could melt up and sell as bullion, you see.
至于宝石，一次卖一个
And the rocks, sell them one at a time.
不用着急，宝石是不会贬值的
There'd be no hurry. They'd last a lifetime.
我怎么会如此愚蠢？
How wrong can a guy be?
我还一直为你担心呢
Here I was worrying about your nerves,
而你却一直在思考如何背叛同伙
and you were dreaming up a double-cross like this.
是的
Yes.
但我做不成，因为我没有五万美元
But I can't do it because I haven't got $50,000.
- 我可以告诉你如何筹钱　- 你？
- I can tell you how to raise it.  - You?
如何筹钱？
How?
- 我能得到什么好处？　- 五五分账
- What's in it for me?  - Fifty-fifty.
好
Okay.
但我们有可能被杀死，朋友
But we may get ourselves killed, my friend.
是的，我…我知道
Yes, I -- I know.
- 到底如何筹钱？　- 很简单，通过考比
- Well, how do we raise the money?  - Simple. Cobby.
- 考比　- 相信我
- Cobby.  - Believe me.
他轻而易举就能搞到钱
He can dig it up without half-trying.
是的
Yes.
但如何跟他解释？我为什么需要钱？
But what do we tell him? Why do I need money?
交给我吧，考比总想成为大人物
Leave it to me. Cobby wants to feel big.
这就是他的机会
Here's his chance.
为伟大的阿隆佐·埃默瑞克筹集预付款
Advancing money for the great Alonzo P. Emmerich.
他会乐于这么做的
Ah, he'll do it.
他会为此出汗，但是他会做的
He'll sweat, but he'll do it.
你开过什么保险箱？
What boxes have you opened?
防加农炮的，双门的，还有几种防火的，什么都有
Cannonball. Double door. Even a few fire chests. All of them.
你能打开那种带定时锁的金库吗？
Can you open a vault with a time lock and a relocking device?
- 当然能　- 你从哪里打开，锁还是缝？
- Sure.  - What do you use, lock or seam?
- 缝　- 曾经打开过吗？
- Seam.  - Ever taken one?
- 记得沙浮特失窃案吗？　- 是的，我坐牢时听说过
- Remember the Shafter job?  - Yes, I heard about it behind the walls.
那一票干得很棒
It was a good score.
- 谁给你提供液体炸药？　- 我自己配制
- Who supplies your soup?  - I thrash it myself.
- 你的撬锁水平如何？　- 我能在四分钟内撬开任何锁
- How are you as a picklock?  - I can open anything in four minutes.
- 他没问题　- 欢迎加入
- He'll do.  - You're in.
别急，我分账多少？
Not so fast. What's the cut?
不按比例分账，你会获得担保酬金
No cut. You get a flat guarantee.
- 我想要三万块钱　- 三万块钱？路易…
- I want 30,000.  - Thirty thousand? Now, Louis --
我们最多能出两万五千块钱
Twenty-five is what we figured.
- 好吧，首款一万五千块钱　- 首款一万块钱
- All right, 15 down.  - Ten down.
我认为一万五千块钱没问题
Fifteen is satisfactory, I think.
找他领钱吧
There's your paymaster.
你为什么流汗？
What are you sweating for?
钱让我流汗，我一直就这样
Money makes me sweat, that's all. It's the way I am.
- 博士，干这一票的都有谁？　- 还没找到人手
- Who are the others on this job, Doc?  - Haven't got them yet.
就我而言，车手的唯一人选是戈斯·米尼西
There's only one driver, as far as I'm concerned -- Gus Minissi.
- 问考比，他认识戈斯　- 戈斯？十分靠谱
- Ask Cobby. He knows him.  - Gus? Hundred percent.
- 那就叫上他　- 他能承担重压，绝不泄密
- Get hold of him.  - He'll take the heat and won't flap his lip.
- 那就叫上他　- 好的，博士
- Get hold of him.  - Sure, Doc.
认识可靠的恶棍吗？
Any ideas about a hooligan?
我认识一个非常棒的大块头，我很久没见他了
I know a very good heavy. I haven't seen him in some time.
- 瑞德·特雷纳　- 他还在养伤
- Red Traynor.  - He's taking the cure.
- 把他排除　- 提曼斯怎么样？
- Rule him out.  - What about Timmons?
- 那是谁？　- 我的门卫
- Who's that?  - My doorman.
那个落魄的摔跤手？你在开玩笑吧？
That busted-down wrestler? Are you kidding?
他是一个四肢发达、头脑简单的家伙
He's got nothing upstairs but solid knuckle.
我是外地人，不像你们一样了解本地
I'm a stranger and do not know as much as you gentlemen.
那个叫迪克斯的南方人怎么样？
But what about this Southerner, this Dix?
他给我的印象是一个非常坚毅的男人，而且也不愚蠢
He impressed me as a very determined man and far from stupid.
实话说，我不喜欢那家伙，但我从未喜欢过任何恶棍
Frankly, I don't like the guy, but I never saw a hooligan I did like.
他们就像左撇子投球手，身上总有某种缺陷
They're like left-handed pitchers. They all have a screw loose somewhere.
我猜迪克斯跟别的人一样好
I suppose he's as good as anybody though.
戈斯觉得迪克斯很棒，而戈斯通常是对的
Gus thinks he's tops, and Gus is usually right.
我喜欢这个人，我们叫上他吧
I like him. I say we take him.
我随便，你是老板
Suits me. You're the boss.
我最好回家，我太太还在担心孩子呢
Well, I better be getting home now. Mrs. Ciavelli's worried about the kid.
- 孩子怎么了？　- 他又着凉了
- What's the trouble?  - Oh, he's got a cold again.
我太太早晨带孩子出门，当时天冷
She takes him out first thing in the morning. It's cold then.
她声称婴儿应该呼吸新鲜空气
She claims a baby's gotta taste fresh air.
就像我总跟她讲的：
Like I'm always telling her,
「如果妳想呼吸新鲜空气，别指望这座城市！」
"If you want fresh air, don't look for it in this town!"
看看照片
Here.
这时他九个月大
He's nine months old there.
我得说，我嫉妒你这样的居家男人
I must say, I envy you being a family man.
是啊
Yeah.
幸福的烦恼，对吧？
Well, always problems, huh?
迪克斯·汉德利有一个好处，给他点钱他就满足了
One good thing about Dix Handley -- you can get him for nickels and dimes.
考比，我问你件事
Tell me something, Cobby.
刚才用的是你的钱，对吗？不是埃默瑞克先生的
It's your money, isn't it? Not Mr. Emmerich's.
- 有什么区别吗？　- 没有
- What difference does it make?  - None, really.
事情是这样，埃默瑞克先生不想让这笔交易出现在他的账面上
It's this way. Mr. Emmerich doesn't want this transaction appearing in his books.
我没有冒风险，他这么做也是怕出岔子
I'm not risking anything. He's good for it in case of a runout.
那你一点也不担心吗？
Then you haven't got a worry?
不担心
No.
- 妳要去哪里？　- 我找到住处了
- Where are you going?  - I found a place.
我有个闺蜜要离开本市，她让我住她的公寓
Girlfriend of mine's leaving town, and she's letting me have her apartment.
房租付到了月初
The rent's paid up till the first of the month.
妳什么时候联系她的？
When did all this happen?
今早，你还没睡醒，我在街上碰见了她
This morning, before you woke up. I bumped into her on the street.
记得那个高挑黑发女人吗？她经常在乐团里跳新潮舞蹈
Remember that tall brunette, used to do the novelty dances at the Bandwagon?
布兰奇·拉露，她人真不错
Blanche La Rue. It sure was nice of her.
我不能总住在你这里，对吧？
I can't go living off you forever, can I?
- 我很高兴能帮助妳　- 嗯
- I was glad to help out.  - Yeah.
也许有机会我也能帮助你
Well, maybe I can do something for you sometime.
妳不欠我什么，算了
You don't owe me a thing. Forget it.
那么…
Well...
再见
good-bye.
- 妳还有钱吗？　- 我有几块钱，足够了
- How are you fixed for dough?  - A couple of bucks. Enough.
- 给，拿上这些钱…　- 不用，谢谢了，迪克斯
- Here, take this and --  - No. No, thanks, Dix.
我一直在打搅你
I'm all through bothering you.
我们吻别一下，如何？
Give us a kiss, huh?
朵儿
Doll.
迪克斯，什么事？
Yes, Dix?
也许我想要跟妳保持联系
Maybe I'll wanna get in touch with you.
噢，当然了，我的新地址
Oh. Oh, sure, my new address.
我住在默顿街４２号
I'll be at 42 Merton Street.
默顿街４２号
42 Merton.
- 喂？　- 是迪克斯吗？
- Hello.  - Hello, Dix?
- 是我　- 我是考比
- Yeah.  - Dix, this is Cobby.
- 你好，考比　- 我找戈斯要到你的电话号码
- Oh. How are ya, Cobby?  - I got your number from Gus.
- 嗯　- 迪克斯，听着
- Yeah.  - Look, Dix.
你想做一笔大买卖吗？我是指真正的大买卖
Do you want to get into something big? I mean, real big.
如果你想做，今晚十点到戈斯的店铺
If you do, be at Gus's tonight at 10:00.
好的
Right.
一切都已计划周密
Everything's here.
蒸汽管道处是软肋，检修井口就在街角
The soft spot's an old steam tunnel. Manhole's on the corner.
十一点四十五分，你进入检修井口，迪克斯帮你把风
You drop into the manhole at 11:45. Dix will cover you.
你把墙壁打穿
You break through the wall.
然后从暖气炉到贝拉提尔珠宝店，这大概要花六分钟
It'll take about six minutes to get into Belletier's from the furnace room.
小心地上的电线
Watch out for floor wires.
从后楼梯上去，躲开警报系统
Make your way up the back stairs and jump the alarm system.
这又要花三分钟
That'll take another three minutes.
十一点五十四分整，迪克斯和我会来到后门
At exactly 11:54, Dix and I will come to the back door.
你要给我们打开门
You open it for us.
- 我会等着你们　- 很好
- I'll be waiting for you.  - Good.
还有问题吗？
Any questions?
- 听上去一切很好　- 我也认为很好
- Everything sounds okay.  - Same here.
那么我就回家了
Well, guess I better be getting home.
- 你儿子怎么样？　- 他没事了
- How's the boy?  - Oh, he's okay.
他昨天发烧，体温相当高
Ran a temperature yesterday. Pretty high too.
我们打电话给医生，但发烧对孩子来说不算什么
We called the doctor, but temperatures don't mean so much with kids.
今天他又恢复正常了
He's back to normal today.
- 明晚十一点半再见　- 晚安
- See you tomorrow night, 11:30.  - Good night.
迪克斯，你有空吗？
Have you got a minute, Dix?
当然，你有什么事？
Sure. What's on your mind?
朋友，你了解埃默瑞克这家伙吗？
My friend, what do you know about this fellow Emmerich?
那个大律师？我仅仅听说过他的名字
You mean the big fixer? I've heard his name, that's all.
- 我可以跟你讲实话吧　- 当然
- I can talk to you, I think.  - Sure.
埃默瑞克先生想独吞我们的珠宝
Mr. Emmerich is taking the jewelry off our hands.
博士，你这话可吓到我了
You sure are surprising me, Doc.
我不完全信任埃默瑞克先生
I don't exactly trust Mr. Emmerich.
只是一种感觉，我可能是错的
It's just a feeling. I may be wrong.
但珠宝要由我们收集，你和我负责
But it's up to us to collect, you and me.
一切都应该很顺利，但如果不顺…
Everything may go smooth, but if it don't...
- 如果他变卦，我们收集珠宝　- 很对
- If he's got it, we'll collect.  - Good.
盗窃行动完成后，我们带着珠宝去找埃默瑞克先生拿钱
We'll meet Mr. Emmerich after the caper, deliver the jewelry and get our money.
他应该立即支付现金
The payment is to be immediate and in cash.
最后，我们付清报酬并各自分开
After that, we pay off and scatter.
别担心，博士，我们收集珠宝
Don't worry, Doc. We'll collect.
（护照）
朗，是你吗？
Lon. Is that you?
- 朗！　- 是我，梅
- Lon!  - Yes, May.
进来，朗
Come in, Lon.
- 我有笔生意要谈　- 坐一会儿
- I've got a business appointment.  - Sit down a minute.
十一点半了，这么晚还谈生意吗？
It's 11:30. Isn't that rather late for business?
- 朗　- 梅，什么事？
- Lon.  - Yes, May?
我身体不舒服
I'm not feeling well.
亲爱的，妳一直都身体不舒服
My dear, you haven't been feeling well for a long time.
我在晚上会紧张
At night, I get nervous.
我一紧张，我就讨厌独自待在这栋大房子里
And when I get nervous, I hate to stay in this big house all by myself.
梅，听着，妳不是独自一人，房子里有三个佣人呢
Look here. May, you're not here alone. There are three servants in the house.
- 妳想要什么就…　- 我知道，按铃
- All you have to...  - I know. Press a button.
那妳想让我做什么？
Well, what do you want me to do?
坐下，朗
Sit down, Lon.
好吧
All right.
我就坐在这里看妳读杂志吗？
Do I sit here and watch you read a magazine?
- 那样很糟糕吗？　- 不是的，梅…
- Would that be so awful?  - Oh, now, look, May --
我们可以玩牌
We could play cards.
- 就像以前一样赌牌　- 换个时间玩吧
- Casino, like we used to.  - Some other night.
朗，求求你，就玩一把
Please, Lon, just one hand.
昨晚我睡不着
I couldn't sleep last night.
然后我就想起了年轻时
Then I got to thinking of the old days,
我们以前很喜欢一起赌牌，就我们俩
how we used to like to stay up and play casino, just the two of us.
是啊，我也想陪妳，但我不能
Yes. I-I wish I could stay, but I can't.
亲爱的，要谈生意
My dear, this is business.
不如这样，我稍后会来看妳
Uh, I tell you what I'll do. I'll look in later,
如果到时妳还醒着，我们就小玩一把
and if you're still awake, we'll have a little game.
（停车场）
请自己拿好钥匙，我们关门了
Take your keys, please. We're closing up.
好的
Okay.
- 准备就绪？　- 对
- All set?  - Yeah.
你最好小心这东西
Better be careful how you handle this stuff.
它能把你炸成碎片
They'll pick you up in little pieces.
你的表几点钟了？
What time have you got?
好的
Good.
祝你好运，博士
Good luck, Doc.
他给你液体炸药了吗？
Did he give you the soup?
这里是红外线电子眼
Here's the electric eye.
液体炸药
Soup.
炸开这金库要多用点
It's gonna take a lot to blow this baby.
芝麻开门
Here goes.
- 什么声音？　- 继续
- What's that?  - Keep going.
博士，整个街区的警报都响了
Hey, Doc, alarms are going off all over the block.
- 爆炸震动了整个警报系统　- 我们怎么办？
- The blast must've shook up the whole system.  - What do we do?
现在离开我会后悔，就快得手了
I would hate to leave now. We're so close.
- 我想做完再走　- 路易，你呢？
- I'm for finishing what we started.  - How about you, Louis?
- 我没问题　- 戈斯会一直等着吗？
- It's okay with me.  - Will Gus hold still?
不用担心戈斯
Don't worry about Gus.
怎么了？
What's the matter?
钻头坏了
The drill broke.
我们应该在十二点十五分前完成，那时夜间保安会来
We should finish before 12:15, before the watchman gets here.
店铺警卫？让我来对付他
The store cop? Let me worry about him.
- 迪克斯，听见了吗？　- 听见了
- Hear that, Dix?  - Yeah.
- 正往这边来吗？　- 从河边过来，听起来不妙
- Coming this way?  - From the river. Don't sound good.
迪克斯，你去看看怎么回事
Dix, take a look, see what's happening.
- 我们得闪人了，快！　- 这就是价值连城的宝贝
- We gotta blow, fast!  - This is everything of real value.
- 很重，是吧？　- 满满一包
- Heavy, ain't she?  - Plenty.
这是损失最大的盗窃案
This is the biggest one yet.
你们等着看报纸头条吧
Wait till you see it in the papers.
是夜间保安，路易，你把门拉开
Watchman. Pull open the door, Louis.
- 也许他会走远　- 照迪克斯的话做
- Maybe he'll go away.  - Do what Dix says.
就现在
Now.
跟着我
Follow me.
- 戈斯，带我回家　- 你哪里受伤？
- Gus, take me home.  - Where'd it get you?
射中大腿，我感觉子弹在往上钻，就像肚子里有虫
In the thigh. I feel it going up. Think I got the slug in my belly.
我带你去见个人，他曾经是医生
I'll take you to a guy, used to be a doctor.
不，带我回家，戈斯，带我回家
No, take me home, Gus. Take me home.
好吧，路易
All right, Louis.
一点多了，他们随时会来
It's after 1:00. They should be here any minute.
除非是出事了
Unless there's been trouble.
安吉拉今晚在哪里？
Where's Angela tonight?
噢，她在她姐姐那里
Hmm? Oh, she's at her sister's.
她这么说而已
She says.
如果我是你，我会少喝些酒
I'd go easy on that liquor if I were you.
喝得半醉，会让我比大多数人更机敏
Half-drunk, I got better wits than most people.
也更有勇气
And more nerve.
朋友，你看起来很紧张，有什么烦恼吗？
You look worried, my friend. Something bothering you?
生活真有趣
Ah, live and learn.
这些年来，我一直有自卑感
All these years, I've been suffering from an inferiority complex.
我应该在几年前就成为有钱人
I should've been in the money years ago.
你这个阔佬，你有什么可烦恼的？
You big boys, what have you got?
最好的，什么都用最好的
Front. Nothing but front.
但当你情况变糟时…
And when that slips --
我相信是我们的客人到了
I do believe our guests are arriving.
一切顺利吗？
Well, everything go all right?
这位是我的朋友，布兰姆先生
This is a friend of mine, Mr. Brannom.
他在本次交易上给了我很大帮助
He's been a great help to me on this deal.
跟我来，先生们
Follow me. Follow me, gentlemen.
这里面要舒服得多
It's much more comfortable in here.
我打赌那里面一定装满了奇珍异宝，对吧？
Say, I'll bet that thing is full of koh-i-noors and Grand Moguls, eh?
有可能
Could be.
先生们，坐下吧
Sit down, gentlemen. Sit down.
- 我给你们倒杯酒　- 不用，谢谢
- Let me get you a drink.  - No, thanks.
- 我们可以看一下吗？　- 你们当然可以看
- Do you mind if we have a look?  - You're entitled to a look, naturally.
- 确认了吗？　- 当然
- Convinced?  - Why, of course. Of course.
我从未怀疑过，我知道这家伙的信誉很好
There never was any doubt in my mind. I know this fellow's reputation.
只是有点好奇而已
Just a matter of curiosity, that's all.
- 我打赌这些估价超过了你的预期　- 行了，行了
- I'll bet the appraisal is going to exceed even your estimate.  - Good, good.
既然如此，我只想看看你的钱
In that case, I'd just like to see the color of your money.
先生们，此刻我必须承认
Gentlemen, I must admit at this moment,
我…我觉得难堪
I, uh -- I'm embarrassed.
你的意思是你还没拿到钱？
You mean you haven't got the money, Mr. Emmerich?
我有钱，我保证能拿到钱
Oh, I have it. That is, I have the assurance of it.
但你还没拿到
You haven't got it.
对，我手上暂时还没有钱
No, I haven't got the currency right here in my hands.
可我发誓绝对能拿到
But it's promised by an unimpeachable source.
先生们，恐怕我们有点仓促，我们…我们行动得太快了
Gentlemen, I'm afraid we were a little hasty. We, uh -- We moved too fast.
- 我们是照你说的做的　- 先等等
- We moved on your word.  - Well now, wait a minute.
那可是一大笔钱，尤其是鉴于目前的状况
That's a large sum of money, you know, considering present-day conditions,
尤其是鉴于我们必须用现金换取这些珠宝
and considering the fact that we had to have it in cash.
因此，恐怕我…还需要几天才能筹够钱
So I'm afraid... a few days more are needed to raise it.
埃默瑞克先生，几天时间对你来说也许不算太长
A few days more may not seem like a very long time to you, Mr. Emmerich.
但对我来说，带着这东西到处走，简直是度日如年
But to me, carrying this around, it would seem like years.
我能理解，我也有解决办法
I understand. I've got a solution for that too.
你们得信任我
That is, if you boys trust me.
如果你们不信任我，除了抱歉外我也无话可说
And if you don't, well, there's nothing I can say except that I'm, uh, sorry.
埃默瑞克先生，你到底想说什么？
Mr. Emmerich, what are you trying to tell us?
当然是关于珠宝
About the jewels.
你们带着珠宝到处走动不安全，你自己也这么说
Wouldn't be safe for you to carry that stuff around. You said so yourself.
- 你的意思是，让我们把珠宝留给你？　- 听我解释
- You mean, we leave them with you?  - Well, now, look here.
当警方明早开始找这些珠宝时
When the police start looking for that stuff tomorrow morning,
他们不会来盘问我
they're not likely to call me up.
他们也不会派侦探来搜查我的房子
They're not likely to send detectives out to search my house, you know.
而博士你…你刚从监狱出来
You, on the other hand, Doc, you, uh -- you're just out of prison.
他们肯定会抓捕像你这样的江洋大盗
They're certainly gonna be looking for the big-timers like yourself.
你刚释放就发生入室盗窃案，某个聪明警察会将此关联起来
Some smart cop might even connect this burglary with your release.
情况就是这样
Well, th-there you are.
当然，正如我所说，这…这取决于你
Of course, as I said, y-you -- it's up to you.
你可以通过考比和我保持联系
You can keep in touch with me through Cobby.
埃默瑞克，你做得很好，但这行不通
You did a great job, Emmerich, but it's not workin'.
- 鲍勃！　- 埃默瑞克，你退后躲开
- Bob!  - Back away and keep out of this, Emmerich.
现在，你这农夫，把双手举起来
Now, you, farmer, get your hands up.
还有你，德国佬…把包扔在地板上
And you, Fritz... throw the bag on the floor.
扔到我脚边
Over here, by my feet.
扔的时候小心点，我可是获得过射击奖章
Be careful how you throw it. I got a pistol expert medal.
- 迪克斯，你说怎么办？　- 他也没办法
- What do you say, Dix?  - He's got no say.
他要是轻举妄动，就别想再拿起铁叉铲粪
He makes a crooked move, he'll never pitch another forkful of manure.
博士，他搞定我们了，把包扔给他
He's got us, Doc. Toss him the bag.
你不像看起来那么笨
You're not as dumb as you look.
你算什么男人？
Are you a man or what?
试图背叛我，却又毫无胆量
Trying to gyp and double-cross me with no guts for it.
你在想什么？你还活着干什么？
What's inside of you? What's keeping you alive?
你为什么不杀死我？
Why don't you kill me?
- 你为什么停下？　- 好吧，先生…
- What's stopping you?  - Okay, mister --
迪克斯，听我说，别杀他，那样太便宜他了
Dix, listen to me. Don't kill him. It's too easy an out for him.
坐下，先生
Sit down, sir.
你为什么耍这种手段？
Whatever possessed you to pull such a stunt?
我…我破产了，面临倒闭
I wa -- I was broke, facing bankruptcy.
博士，他是目击者，他看见我干掉了那家伙，他会告发我！
Doc, he's a witness. He saw me knock off that guy. You think he wouldn't holler?
他现在的处境不会告发你
He's in no position to talk.
你和地板上那个人，本想如何处理珠宝？
What did you and your man there intend to do with the jewels?
离开城市，每次卖掉一点
Leave town. Sell them off a little at a time.
行不通，你卖了第一次后警方就会盯上你
No good. The police would have been on you after the first sale.
风声很紧时，你不能到处叫卖这东西
You can't go peddling stuff like this around when the heat's on.
博士，快闪人吧，别在这里浪费时间
Let's blow, Doc. Let's not fool around here any longer.
迪克斯，耐心点
Be patient, Dix.
埃默瑞克先生带我们落入陷阱，他也要带我们脱身
Mr. Emmerich got us into this hole, and he's going to get us out.
我救你的命并非因为我是人道主义者
I didn't save your life because I'm a lover of humanity.
我们带着整包珠宝会惹上麻烦
We're in trouble with this satchel full of jewels.
目前无法卖掉珠宝，那它们就只是垃圾
As things stand, it's just so much junk.
- 我也无能为力　- 不，你可以出力，埃默瑞克先生
- There's nothing I can do.  - Yes, there is, Mr. Emmerich.
你可以去保险公司谈判
You can go to the insurance company.
- 保险公司？　- 他们有理由和你谈判
- Insurance company?  - They'll listen to reason.
保险公司要为珠宝失窃赔付昂贵的保险金
This is a very bad jolt for them,
他们很可能愿意买下这些珠宝减少损失，而且不会多嘴
and it's possible they'll be willing to buy the jewels back, no questions asked,
大概按四分之一的价值买下
for as high as 25% of what they're worth.
博士，快闪人吧
Doc, let's blow.
我明天去处理
I'll start on it tomorrow.
迅速点，埃默瑞克
Get busy, Emmerich.
记住，你本应和你朋友一起躺死在这里
And remember, you might have been lying here dead with your friend.
我通过考比和你联系吗？
Shall I get in touch with you through Cobby?
不，由我来联系你
No. I'll get in touch with you.
迪克斯，走吧
Come on, Dix.
我建议你料理一下你朋友的后事
I advise you to clean up after your friend.
- 别给他喝水　- 他要喝水
- Don't give him any water.  - He asked for it.
- 我说了别给他喝水　- 放开我
- I said don't give him any water.  - Let go.
妳想害死他吗？他也许胃部受伤了
You wanna kill him? Maybe he's hurt in the stomach.
医生在哪里？他为什么还不来？
Where's the doctor? Why doesn't he come?
你说十分钟就来，可已经过去半小时了
You said ten minutes. It's half an hour.
这样下去路易会死的，为什么不让我送他去医院？
Louis'll die. Why can't I take my Louis to the hospital?
如果妳送路易去医院手术室，那妳就别想再见到他
If you take him to the hospital, into an operating room, you'll never see him again.
玛利亚，别担心，路易会好起来的
Take it easy, Maria. Louis's gonna be all right.
医生会完好如新地治愈他
The doctor will fix him up good as new.
妳和路易会再生六个孩子
You and Louis are gonna have six more kids.
每个都白白胖胖，有黑色大眼睛，浓密的头发
All as fat as pigs, big black eyes, lots of hair.
就像路易一样，玛利亚，如何？
Just like Louis, eh, Maria?
离婴儿远点！
Stay away from the baby!
戈斯，跟我说实话，到底怎么回事？
Tell me the truth, Gus. How did it happen?
- 我跟妳说过，打架受伤　- 路易从不打架，这你知道
- I told you. A fight.  - Louis don't fight. You know that.
好吧
All right.
为什么总是你？
Why is it always you?
每次路易遇到麻烦，总有你的份
Whenever Louis gets into trouble, you're around.
你这肮脏的瘸子！驼子！
You dirty cripple! You crooked back!
- 你就是邪恶化身！　- 玛利亚，闭上妳的嘴！
- You have the evil eye!  - Shut your mouth, Maria!
我不能容忍别人那样说我
I don't let anybody say that to me.
戈斯，对不起
I'm sorry, Gus,
但我必须发泄情绪
but I gotta blame somebody.
我后背上的东西，我出生时就有
What I carry on my back, I was born with it.
不是我要求它长出来的
I didn't grow it myself.
戈斯，请原谅我，我不是故意的
Please forgive me, Gus. I didn't mean it.
- 你听那笛声　- 听到了，肯定失火了
- Listen to that.  - Yeah. Must be a fire.
但不在这附近，在别的地方
It's not in this neighborhood though. Someplace else.
戈斯，我祈祷那个医生快点到来
Oh, Gus. I pray to God that doctor get here quick.
他随时会到，玛利亚
Aw, he'll be here any minute, Maria.
听起来像地狱里幽魂的声音
Sounds like a soul in hell.
迪克斯，你为什么不联系戈斯，让他带你去看那个医生
Dix, why don't you get in touch with Gus and let him take you to that doctor.
别犯傻
Don't be foolish.
我不喜欢医生，我根本没事
I don't like doctors. I'm getting along all right.
子弹只是擦破了我的外皮，然后飞走了
That bullet just ripped through my side and went on about its business.
- 幸好我跳开了　- 事情怎么会变成这样？
- Good thing I jumped.  - How can things go so wrong?
这怎么可能？一个人被杀死，两个人挨枪子
How is it possible? One man killed, two others plugged.
我出了三万块钱，我们得到一堆宝石却无法贩卖
I'm out 30 grand. We got a load of rocks we can't even peddle.
别发牢骚了，给我倒点波旁威士忌
Why don't you quit cryin' and get me some bourbon.
我真是愚蠢至极
I must be awful stupid.
我这里有很好的生意
Here I am with a good business,
财源滚滚
money rolling in.
我却卷进了这样的破事里
I-I gotta get mixed up in a thing like this.
我真该检查一下我的脑子
I ought to have my head examined.
喂，你好，对，我是考比
Yeah, hello, hello. Yeah, this is Cobby.
什么？
What?
是戈斯，抓捕网已经撒开，警方正在搜查整个地区
It's Gus. Dragnet's out, and they're combing the district.
迪克斯，他要跟你说话
He wants to talk to you. You, Dix.
- 戈斯？我是迪克斯　- 仔细听我说，哥们儿
- Gus? Dix.  - Yeah, now listen careful, pal.
警方正在搜查街道上的每家店铺和车辆
The cops are knocking over joints along the boulevard, meat wagons and all.
听着，我给一个人打过电话，他叫艾迪·德纳托
Now, look. I already called a guy, Eddie Donato.
德纳托在河边有一家食品杂货店，在前街１１６号
Donato's got a grocery down by the river. 116 Front Street.
- 你记住了吗？　- 是的，戈斯，谢谢，路易怎么样？
- You got that? Okay.  - Yeah. Thanks, Gus. How's Louis?
路易不太好，他肚子里有一颗子弹，医生正在尽全力
Louis is not so good. He got a slug in his belly. Doc's doing all he can.
现在他们来了，那些警察小子
Yeah, here they are now, the happiness boys.
喂，你好吗？看来我要加班了
Hello. How are you? Looks like I'm in for a working-over.
听着，去艾迪的店铺要走旧车库那条路
Look, go down to Eddie's by way of the old car barn.
晚上那里没人，只要你通过那里就会没事
It's deserted at night. Once you get beyond that, you're okay.
警察从不到艾迪店铺的附近去
The cops never bother Eddie's neighborhood.
再见，迪克斯，赶紧闪人吧
So long, Dix. Blow now, huh?
来了，来了，来了
All right, all right, all right.
（艾迪·德纳托食品杂货店）
什么？请大声点
What? Uh, please, talk a little louder.
我是艾迪·德纳托
This is Eddie Donato.
噢，当然，我叫博士来接
Oh, sure, sure. I'll get-a Doc for you.
[ 意大利语 ] 博士，是你的人
Hey, dottore, I got your man.
喂？
Hello?
是的
Yes.
可以，很好
Fine, fine. Good.
那也足够满意
That'll be satisfactory.
- 考比？　- 是的
- Cobby?  - Yes.
埃默瑞克搞定了，保险公司说可以买回珠宝
Emmerich came through. The insurance people say okay.
当然，必须等到星期一早上银行开门
Of course, we'll have to wait till the banks open Monday morning,
只有二十五万美元，但也不错
but it's 250,000, which is not bad.
怎么了？
What's the matter?
朗，作为律师，你也许非常精明
As a lawyer, you may be very brilliant, Lon,
- 但作为赌牌玩家，你还要学习很多事　- 是啊
- but as a casino player, you have a lot to learn.  - Yeah.
- 妳不介意我抽烟吧？　- 当然不介意，朗
- You don't mind if I smoke, do you?  - Of course not, Lon.
- 出牌　- 朗
- Oh, here.  - Lon.
你怎么能这样玩？这手牌你一分也得不到
How could you make a play like that? You won't make a single point this hand.
进来
Come in.
先生，有两位男士要见你，他们是从警察部门来的
Two gentlemen to see you, sir. They are from the police department.
朗，他们来干什么？
What on earth could they want, Lon?
我猜可能和某个辩护案件有关吧
Oh, something to do with a case, I suppose.
- 失陪一下　- 真扫兴，我们玩得正开心呢
- Excuse me?  - Oh, bother. We were having so much fun.
- 快点回来　- 当然
- Hurry back.  - Sure.
- 什么事？　- 埃默瑞克先生，很抱歉打扰你
- Yes?  - Sorry to disturb you, Mr. Emmerich.
我是安德鲁，这位是詹诺切克警官
I'm Andrews. This is Officer Janocek.
- 幸会　- 你好
- How do you do?  - How are you?
呃，我能为你们做什么？
Well, uh, what can I do for you?
你认识一个叫鲍勃·布兰姆的人吗？
Do you know a man named Robert Brannom?
布兰姆，当然认识
Brannom. Yes, of course.
怎么了？发生大事了吗？
What is it? Something the matter?
是的，埃默瑞克先生
There sure is, Mr. Emmerich.
今早在河里发现他的尸体
His body was pulled out of the river this morning.
- 老天呐　- 但不是淹死的
- Great heavens.  - But it was no drowning.
他胸前有个洞，他是被枪杀的
He had a hole through his pump. He'd been shot.
呃，你们能进去谈吗？
Will you, uh, step in here for a minute?
我得说，这真是…
Well, I must say, this is, uh --
这真令人吃惊，鲍勃·布兰姆？
It's quite a shock. Bob Brannom, eh?
你说他是被谋杀的？老天呐
Murdered, you say? Great heavens.
我们在他的衣兜里发现一张名单，是用你的商业信笺写的
We found a list of names in his pocket written on your business stationery.
- 这些人是谁？你认识吗？　- 这是我的欠债者名单
- Who are these people, do you know?  - Oh, that's a list of my debtors.
布兰姆为我工作，他正在收回那些旧债
Brannom was working for me. He was trying to collect some old debts.
我得说，没取得太大成功
Without much success, I must say.
他跟这名单上的什么人有过节吗？
Was he giving the treatment to anybody on this list?
「过节」？当然没有
"Giving the treatment"? Certainly not.
你觉得他为你工作这件事与他的死没有任何关联吗？
You don't think there's any connection between this work for you and his death?
- 完全没关联　- 你最后一次见他是什么时候？
- None whatever.  - When did you see him last?
上周三夜晚，就在这房间里
Well now, last Wednesday evening in this room.
- 我们一起看了遍那份名单　- 嗯哼
- Yes. We went over that list together.  - Mm-hmm.
验尸官说，他是今天凌晨一点或两点钟被打死的
The coroner says he was plugged about 1:00 or 2:00 this morning.
比贝拉提尔珠宝店失窃案稍晚一些
Not much after the Belletier job was pulled.
我们认为这之间可能有关联
We figure there might be a connection.
我们知道其中一个盗贼受了枪伤
One of the heist guys was shot. We know that.
珠宝店的地板上有血迹，也许就是布兰姆的
There was blood on the floor. Maybe it was Brannom's.
他可能死在逃跑的车中，然后同伙把他扔进了河里
He could've died in the getaway car and the others dropped him in the river.
噢，不，不
Oh, no, no, no.
鲍勃·布兰姆虽是粗野之人，但他不是罪犯
Bob Brannom's a good deal of a roughneck, but he's no criminal,
据我判断，贝拉提尔珠宝店失窃案是职业大盗所为
and if I'm any judge, Belletier's was the work of big-time professionals.
不，先生们，鲍勃·布兰姆卷进了入室盗窃案
Oh, no, no, gentlemen. Bob Brannom mixed up in any burglary.
这是难以想象的事
Why, that's inconceivable.
我明白了
I see.
埃默瑞克先生，还有一件事，当然只是为了留作记录
Oh, uh, one more thing, Mr. Emmerich. Just for the record, of course.
可以告诉我们昨晚你在哪里吗？
Could you give us an account of your whereabouts last night?
可以
Yes, I could.
为什么？有这个必要吗？
Why? Is it necessary?
恐怕有必要，埃默瑞克先生
I'm afraid so, Mr. Emmerich.
小伙子们，我这把年纪的人很讨厌坦白这种事
Well, boys, a man of my years hates to make an admission like this,
有一位芬利小姐住在我河边的小别墅里
but a Miss Phinlay is living in my cottage on the river.
昨晚我去拜访她了，大概是十一点半
And last night, I went to visit her at about, uh, 11:30, I think it was.
待到很晚
Stayed rather late.
当然，她会证实这一点
Oh, she'll verify this, of course.
但小伙子们…稍微谨慎点，好吗？
Oh, but, boys -- use a little discretion, eh?
当然，除非这有某种用途
Unless, of course, it serves some useful purpose.
我理解，埃默瑞克先生，非常感谢你的帮助
I understand, Mr. Emmerich, and thank you very much for your help.
没什么，谢谢你们
Not at all. Thank you.
另外，如果我还能帮上什么忙，你们随时找我
And say, if I can be any further help, you just call on me.
- 祝今天愉快　- 祝今天愉快
- Good day.  - Good day.
- 喂，是安吉拉吗？　- 是的
- Hello, Angela?  - Yes.
- 我是朗　- 朗大叔，你为什么不给我打电话？
- This is Lon.  - Uncle Lon, why haven't you called?
宝贝，听着，警方可能会拜访妳
Listen, baby, you may have a visit from the police.
- 是因为你妻子吗？　- 不是
- Is it your wife?  - No, no.
不是那样的
No, it's nothing like that.
他们很可能会问妳一些关于昨晚的事
They'll probably ask you some questions about last night.
宝贝，现在听着
Now, listen, baby.
我要妳告诉他们昨晚我和妳在一起
I want you to tell them that I was there with you
从晚上十一点半直到凌晨三点
from, uh, 11:30 until 3:00 in the morning.
- 几乎一整夜　- 是的，几乎一整夜
- That's most of the night.  - Most of the night. That's right.
- 妳听明白了吗？　- 当然，我明白
- Now, is that clear?  - Sure, it's clear.
不，宝贝，这只是有关政治
Yes. Oh, no, no. Just politics, baby.
- 千年不变的肮脏政治游戏　- 好吧，到时给我打电话
- Good old dirty politics.  - All right. Call me right away.
好的，我稍后给妳打电话
Yes. Yes, I'll call you later.
- 别忘了　- 是
- Don't forget.  - Yes.
我们继续玩吗？
Can we go on playing?
当然，为什么不呢？
Certainly. Why not?
朗，你的脸色像鬼一样苍白
Why, Lon, you're as pale as a ghost.
怎么回事？
What's the matter?
我…
Oh, I --
我刚听到一个坏消息
Well, I just had some bad news.
一个为我工作的人死去了
A man who works for me got killed.
朗，太可怕了，是意外吗？
Oh, Lon, how awful. Was it an accident?
不是
No.
不，那是…
No, it was, uh,
蓄意谋杀
an intentional killing.
- 他们知道凶手是谁吗？　- 不知道
- Do they know who did it?  - No.
朗，我一想到你和那些可怕的人打交道…
Oh, Lon, when I think of all those awful people you come in contact with --
那些十足的罪犯…我感到害怕
downright criminals -- I get scared.
噢，他们其实没什么不同
Oh, there's nothing's so different about them.
毕竟，犯罪只是…
After all, crime is only...
人类行为的一种偏差而已
a left-handed form of human endeavor.
- 迪克斯，你去过墨西哥城吗？　- 没有
- Ever been in Mexico City, Dix?  - Nope.
它海拔八千英尺高，空气非常纯净
It's 8,000 feet up. The air is very pure.
有许多一流俱乐部和饭店，还有一处赛马场
Many first-class clubs and restaurants, a horse track
以及姑娘们
and girls.
年轻美貌的姑娘们
Beautiful young girls.
如果有人为你付账，你愿意去那里吗？
How would you like to go there, all expenses paid?
抱歉，博士，不感兴趣，我要回老家
Sorry, Doc, not interested. I'm headin' home.
迪克斯，你总是能回老家的
Listen, Dix. You can always go home.
可等你真回去了，又觉得毫无意义
And when you do, it's nothing.
相信我，我回过老家，毫无意义
Believe me. I've done it. Nothing.
我已经决定了
My mind's made up.
是我
It's me.
看呐，朋友们
Look, my friends.
朋友们
My friends,
我是个可敬的人
I am a respectable man.
为了戈斯，我做了人情
For Gus, I do a favor, all right.
（悬赏珠宝盗窃疑犯）
- 看看报纸上的照片…　- 艾迪，你是想要我们闪人吗？好吧
- With this picture in the paper --  - You want us to blow, right, Eddie? Okay.
我们越早离开这里越好
The sooner we get out of here, the better.
我们的朋友艾迪要去鼓励举报的地方了
Our friend Eddie's getting to the place where he'd talk with encouragement.
不，我不会举报的
Oh, no. I no talk.
否则戈斯会割破我的肚子
Gus cut my belly open.
朋友们，我很抱歉给你们带来这个坏消息
I'm sorry, my friends, to bring you this bad news.
- 我现在就走　- 坐下，德纳托
- I go now, please.  - Sit down, Donato.
我没叫你走，你哪里也不准去
You're not going anyplace till I say so.
待着，艾迪
Stay put, Eddie.
只要你老实坐在这里并闭上你的嘴，就没人会伤害你
Nobody's gonna hurt you so long as you sit still and keep your mouth shut.
我觉得是保险公司向警方告发了那个大骗子
The way I figure, the insurance guys must have sicced the cops on that big phony,
然后他就泄露了
and he spilled.
博士，你就不该阻止我一枪打死他
You never should've stopped me, Doc, when I was gonna blast him.
不，埃默瑞克没有泄露
No, Dix, he hasn't spilled,
- 否则警方不会只找我一个人　- 那是怎么回事？
- or they wouldn't be looking for just me.  - Then how come?
因为只有三、四个人能干此类大案子
Because there's only three or four men who can manage a job like this.
警局里某个有点脑子的人已经认定我就是疑犯
Somebody in the department with a few brains has decided I'm the guy.
我已经想到这点了
I've been half expecting it.
我并不怎么担心
It doesn't worry me much.
我们明天就能拿到钱
We'll get our money tomorrow, you bet.
我希望如此
I hope so.
- 迪克斯，我们去哪里？　- 我知道一个地方
- Where we going, Dix?  - I know a place.
艾迪，如果你足够聪明，就当作从未见过我们
Eddie, if you're a smart boy, you'll forget you ever seen us.
- 我想见局长　- 陈述你的目的
- I wanna see the commissioner.  - State your business.
我是一个公民，如果我想那我就可以见局长，不是吗？
Look, I'm a citizen. I can see the commissioner if I want to, can't I?
- 是关于瑞登施奈德吗？　- 有可能
- Is it about Riedenschneider?  - Could be.
那家伙当然在附近
He sure gets around, that guy.
大概有五千人在过去二十四小时内见过他
About 5,000 people have seen him in the last 24 hours.
你去那里排队等候，轮到你时你就可以讲了
If you get in that line over there and wait your turn, you can tell your story.
除局长以外我不会跟任何人讲
I won't tell anybody but the commissioner.
好吧，伙计，坐下等候，但可能要花些时间
Okay, okay. Sit down and wait, buddy. But it may be some time.
好的
Okay.
我想要见局长
I'd like to see the commissioner.
你们要去哪里？
Where do you think you're going?
- 我们正要回家　- 是吗？
- We're on our way home.  - Yeah?
- 你们住在哪里？　- 卡姆登南边
- Where do you live?  - South on Camden.
你们没事别来这里，这里是市政府财产，到处都已标记
You guys got no business in here. This is city property. There are signs.
- 人人都在用　- 可不是嘛
- Everybody uses it.  - You're telling me.
甚至一群恶棍都带年轻姑娘们来这里厮混
Even a bunch of hoodlums have been bringing young girls here.
- 那是真的吗？　- 是的
- Is that a fact?  - Yeah.
我们的一个同袍因为争执而丢了工作
It's cost one of our boys his job on account of the beefs.
如果我是你们，我就会远离这里，明白吗？
If I were you guys, I'd stay out of here. You understand?
好的，警官
Okay, Officer.
嘿，等等
Hey, wait a minute.
你，拎包的那个，过来
You, with the bag, come here.
迪克斯
Oh, Dix.
迪克斯，亲爱的
Oh, Dix, honey.
你得原谅我
You'll have to excuse me.
我吃了几片安眠药，我仍然感觉晕乎乎的
I took a couple of sleeping pills, and I guess I'm still kind of groggy.
我最近总睡不着，迪克斯
I haven't been able to sleep much lately, Dix,
我担心着你的一切
worrying about you and everything.
我去过你住的地方，他们跟我说警方正在抓你
I was up at your place. They told me the cops were after you.
给我弄些冷水和毛巾，不要瞎扯了
Get me some cold water and some towels and stop yapping.
当然可以，迪克斯
Well, sure, Dix. Sure.
- 快点去　- 好的
- Get a move on.  - Oh, you bet.
花了那么长时间策划
Put in hours and hours of planning.
详细计算每一件事情，然后怎么样？
Figure everything down to the last detail. Then what?
防盗警报无缘无故地四处乱响
Burglar alarms start going off all over the place for no sensible reason.
一把枪自动开火，而一个人被击中
A gun fires of its own accord, and a man is shot,
还有一个下流老头，除了追求女孩子什么也不擅长
and a broken-down old harness bull, no good for anything but chasing kids,
这些差点绊倒我们，纯属意外
has to trip over us. Blind accident.
出现意外状况你能怎么办？
What can you do against blind accident?
我应该意识到但却没做的一件事就是埃默瑞克
One thing I ought to have figured and didn't was Emmerich.
我知道我为什么没意识到，我不能再欺骗自己
I know why I didn't. I'm not kidding myself.
是因为他承诺会给额外的钱
It was the extra dough he promised.
我太饥渴了，贪婪使我盲目
I got hungry. Greed made me blind.
嘿，迪克斯，他不就是报纸上悬赏的那个人吗？
Hey, Dix. Dix, isn't he the one with the reward on him?
妳别管闲事
Mind your own business.
她证实了埃默瑞克说的话，深夜十一点半到三点，他们在一起
She confirmed what Emmerich said, that he was with her from 11:30 till 3:00.
- 她给你的印象如何？　- 非常深刻
- How did she impress you?  - Very much.
- 她真是个宝贝　- 我不是这个意思
- She's some babe.  - That's not what I mean.
她的态度坦率吗？
Was her manner straightforward?
噢，我猜她说的是真话
Oh, I guess she was telling the truth, all right.
结婚二十年了
Married 20 years.
却还包养一个足够做他孙女的年轻女人，真恶心
Consorting with a woman young enough to be his granddaughter. It's disgusting.
但埃默瑞克这种人并不会让我惊讶
But nothing about Emmerich would surprise me.
他受过教育，懂得用脑子规避法律
Educated man who uses his brains to circumvent the law.
最差的一种人，不用为他辩解
Worst type of human being. No excuse for him.
- 局长，打扰一下　- 什么事？
- Excuse me, Commissioner.  - Well?
外面有个出租车司机在等候
There's a taxi driver been waiting outside.
- 他说有一些重要情报　- 关于什么的？
- Says he's got some important information.  - Concerning what?
我试过问他，但他说除你以外不会跟任何人讲
I-I tried to find out, but he wouldn't talk to anyone but you.
他等候两个小时了
He's been waiting two hours.
- 好吧，让他进来　- 是，长官
- All right, send him in.  - Yes, sir.
- 你叫什么名字？　- 查尔斯·怀特
- What's your name?  - Charles Wright.
出租车司机工号１４８０３，绿带公司
Hackie number 14803. Green Stripe Company.
你的情报是什么？
What's this information you've got?
所有人都在找的那个小老头博士，他坐过我的车
The little doctor everybody's looking for. I think I had him for a fare.
- 你把他载到了某个地方？　- 现在我很肯定就是他
- You drove him someplace?  - Well, now I'm pretty sure it was him
一周前的星期五，我在火车站载的他
I picked up at the station a week ago Friday.
- １６号星期五？　- 是的，先生
- Friday the 16th?  - Yes, sir.
- 你把他载到哪里？　- 卡姆登西区的一个门牌号
- Where'd you take him?  - To a number on Camden West.
我记得是因为我问过是否需要我等他
I remember because I asked if he wanted me to wait.
我认识的一个人在卡姆登西区被打劫过
I know a fella that got rolled once on Camden West.
他身上没钱，劫匪就抢走了他的裤子和鞋子
He didn't have nothin', so they stole his pants and shoes.
你把他载到哪里？门牌号是什么？
Where did you take him? What number?
４７１７，像是一间仓库，当时天很黑
4717. Kind of a storeroom. It was dark.
- 再说一遍门牌号？　- ４７１７
- What's that number again?  - 4717.
局长，那里曾是个赌注登记场所
Used to be a bookie joint, Commissioner.
给我接通迪崔克警长
Get hold of Lieutenant Ditrich.
对，就是他
Yeah, that's him.
刚开始我还觉得来这里是很傻的一件事
At first I thought I was making a fool of myself by coming here.
但那人就是他，局长
But that's him all right, Commissioner.
- 你可能得到赏金，我希望如此　- 迪崔克警长在一号线
- You may be in for a reward. I hope so.  - Lieutenant Ditrich on one.
- 迪崔克，你在哪里？　- 我在第四街车站，局长
- Where are you, Ditrich?  - I'm at 4th Street Station, Commissioner.
现在办一张搜查令，然后去卡姆登西区４７１７号
All right. Now, get a search warrant and go to 4717 Camden West.
- 瑞登施奈德去过那里　- 是４７１７号吗？
- Riedenschneider was seen there.  - That's 4717?
是的，你进去前把你的人盯好，快点行动
Yeah. Stake your men out before you go in. Get a move on.
刚接到消息
News just came in.
一个巡警在车库执勤时碰到两个人，被他们打伤
A patrolman was on duty at the car barn. He ran into two men and was slugged.
他们逃跑了，但巡警认出其中的小个子是瑞登施奈德
They got away, but he identified the smaller one as Riedenschneider.
非常好，我们要封锁整片地区
Good. Great. We'll block off the whole area.
别拉警笛，我们要秘密行动
And no sirens. We'll make it a sneak.
- 那个巡警怎么样？伤得严重吗？　- 他头部受伤，有些虚弱
- How about the patrolman? Badly hurt?  - A head wound and he's kinda punchy,
但医生认为头骨没有破
but the doctor doesn't think he's got a fracture.
孩子们，看来这起案件终于有进展了
Well, son, looks like maybe we're getting somewhere at last.
警长，我怎么会知道贝拉提尔珠宝店失窃案的事？
Look, Lieutenant, what-what would I know about Belletier's?
我可不会卷进盗窃案，你知道的
I wouldn't mix in no robbery. You know that.
- 你不会吗？　- 不，当然不会！
- Wouldn't you?  - No, of course not!
你确实在这里见过瑞登施奈德，但那并不意味着…
You saw Riedenschneider here, sure. But that don't say --
你这笨蛋，我从未在这里见过任何人
You're nuts. Never seen anybody here.
我怎么可能？在此之前我从未来过这里
How could I? I never been here before this.
噢
Well,
既然是这样
that being the case,
怎么会把我和贝拉提尔珠宝店失窃案关联在一起？
what's to connect me with the Belletier job?
有人见过他来到这里，我不知道是谁
Somebody saw him here. I don't know who.
也许你这附近有告密者
Maybe you got a fink around.
警长，你确定不喝杯酒吗？
Look. You're sure you won't have one, Lieutenant?
不，谢谢，我…执勤时从不喝酒，那是违反规定的
No, thanks, I... never drink while on duty. It's against regulations.
听着，我没什么可隐瞒的，瑞登施奈德待过这里
Look. I got nothing to hide. Riedenschneider holed up here.
他破产了，我让他在这里的房间住了两天
He was broke. I let him use a room for a couple days.
后来我厌倦了他待在这里，给了一些钱把他打发走了
I got tired of having him around. I gave him a few bucks to get rid of him.
- 他去了哪里？　- 我不知道
- Where'd he go?  - I don't know.
我不知道！
I don't know!
考比，你把我当作哥们儿，是不是？
Look, Cobby, do you figure me for a pal, or don't you?
- 当然了，警长　- 那就接受我的建议，改变立场
- I sure do, Lieutenant.  - Then take my advice and turn state's.
我们会和局长达成一份小协议
We'll make ourselves a little deal with the commissioner.
- 你最多被判刑一到两年　- 我是清白的
- You won't get more than a year or two.  - Look, I-I'm clean.
我不知道博士去了哪里，这是真话
I don't know where the doc went. That's the truth.
总部的人不会相信你
They won't believe you at headquarters.
如果你说你不知道，他们会严格审问你
Every time you'd tell them that, they'd work you over,
相信我，你不是吃苦的料
and you ain't the type that can take it, believe me.
半小时内你就会吐露一切
You'd spill your guts in half an hour.
饶了我吧
Gi-Give me a break.
你当然是来抓人的，但我不在这里
You came to make a pinch, sure. But I'm not here.
我去夏安市做生意了
I had to go to Cheyenne on business.
不，考比，你就在这里
Uh-uh. You're right here, Cobby.
我一直对你很好，警长
I've always treated you right, Lieutenant.
帮我脱身
Let me duck out.
- 你可以逃过处罚　- 不，我不能
- You can get away with it.  - No, I couldn't.
局长发疯了，他要放人血
The commissioner's mad. He's out for blood.
而且不能放我的血
And it's not going to be mine.
你阻止不了我
You're not gonna stop me.
你必须放我走！你必须这样做！
You're gonna let me go! You're gonna do that!
否则…
If you don't...
我知道，否则你会揭发我
Yeah, I know. You'll be a Grade-A pigeon.
没错
That's right.
我会揭发你在这里见过瑞登施奈德
I'll tell 'em you saw Riedenschneider here
但你却没赶走他，为什么？
and didn't roust him. Why?
因为你必须解释你来这里干什么
Because you'd have to explain what you were doing here.
我会揭发你从我这里得到了甜头
I'll tell 'em about the juice you've been getting out of me.
考比，你现在做的事让我很恼火
Cobby, the only thing you're doing is making me sore.
一旦我打开话匣子，我就不会停
Once I start singing, I won't stop.
- 他们会把你和我关在一起　- 考比，那你就错了
- They'll jug you right alongside of me.  - That's where you're wrong, Cobby.
就算他们相信你，也不会太为难我
Even if they believe you, it won't go too hard with me.
因为我将成为破获全国最大盗窃案的人
Because I'll be the guy that cracked the biggest case ever pulled in the country.
- 考比，这会很疼　- 迪崔克！干嘛？你疯了吗？
- Gonna get hurt, Cobby.  - Ditrich! What, have you gone crazy?
- 站起来！　- 啊！
- Stand up!  - Aaah!
考比，我说过你吃不了苦
I told you you couldn't take it, Cobby.
喝杯酒
Here.
他们会骂我是告密者
They'll call me a fink.
这才像话
That's my boy.
既然我最近有很多案子要忙，我想妳应该出去旅行
So, since I'm gonna be busy with a lot of cases, I thought you'd like to take a trip.
- 去哪里？　- 我不知道
- Where to?  - I don't know.
美国太平洋沿岸，佛罗里达州，妳想去哪里都行
The coast, Florida. Anywhere you like.
朗大叔，真的吗？任何地方？你没骗我？
Could I, Uncle Lon? Anywhere? No fooling?
是的，我觉得换个环境对妳有好处
Yes. I think a change of scenery might be good for you.
你在这里等着，我有个非常棒的主意
Wait. You wait right here. I've got the most terrific idea.
噢，古巴，那是一个不错的主意
Oh. Cuba. There, that's not a bad idea.
想象一下我在这片沙滩上穿着绿色泳装，妙极了
Imagine me on this beach here in my green bathing suit. Yipe.
我差点买了一件白色的，但不够新潮
I almost bought a white one, but it wasn't quite extreme enough.
如果我真要追逐新潮，我会买一件法国式比基尼
If I went in for the extreme extreme, I would have bought a French one.
逃命吧，姑娘们，性感炸弹来了
Run for your lives, girls. The fleet's in.
朗大叔，我太兴奋了，妙极了！
Oh, Uncle Lon, am I excited. Yipe!
看呐，这是不是很浪漫？真正的棕榈树、海洋、一切美好事物
Look, Uncle Lon. Isn't it romantic? Real palms and ocean and everything.
这么晚了会是谁？
Who can that be this time of night?
朗大叔，去看看是谁
See who it is, Uncle Lon.
他们为什么如此用力敲门？
Why are they pounding so?
朗大叔，我害怕
I'm scared, Uncle Lon.
年轻人，你有一只铁拳啊
Well, young man, you've got an iron fist.
噢，你好，哈迪，进来吧
Oh, hello, Hardy. Come in.
里面有火，进去吧，你们看起来很冷
Well, there's a fire in here. Come on in. You look cold.
埃默瑞克，我是来逮捕你的
I'm here to arrest you, Emmerich.
我能问为什么吗？
May I ask what for?
盗窃案和谋杀案的共犯
Complicity. In robbery and in murder.
哈迪，如果我是你，我会想出更多控诉
If I were you, Hardy, I'd think up a few more charges.
可能会有一项控诉站得住脚
You might make one of them stand up
如果你面对的是愚蠢的陪审团和公正的法官的话
if you get an imbecile jury and the right judge.
- 把年轻女士带来　- 是，长官
- Get the young lady.  - Yes, sir.
你也许想知道，你的朋友考比已经签了认罪书
It may interest you to know that your friend Cobb has signed a confession.
想看看吗？给你
Want to take a look at it? Here.
小姐，破门而入可没什么风度，但不要逼我
Okay, miss, it's a shame to bust this door in, but here goes.
大香蕉头，你还没烦够我吗？
Haven't you bothered me enough, you big banana head?
只要你敢踢破我的门，埃默瑞克先生就会把你扔出房子
Just try breaking my door, and Mr. Emmerich will throw you out the house.
恐怕不会，小姐，他自己的麻烦够多了
'Fraid not, miss. He's got troubles enough.
事实上，他是一只死鸭子了
As a matter of fact, he's a dead duck.
安德鲁，快点，把年轻女士带过来
Hurry up, Andrews. Bring the young lady in here.
我必须和他说话吗？
Do I have to talk to him?
我不能只和你说话吗？
Couldn't I just talk to you?
来吧，宝贝
Come on, baby.
克服一下
Get it over with.
还有…放聪明点
And... be smart.
告诉局长真相，只要这样做就行
Tell the commissioner the truth. That's the only thing to do.
来吧
Come on.
坐下
Sit down.
安德鲁，复述一下芬利小姐昨天下午录的口供
Andrews, repeat the statement Miss Phinlay made yesterday afternoon.
她说上周五晚上从十一点半到凌晨三点
She said Mr. Emmerich was in this house with her
埃默瑞克先生和她一起在这栋房子里
from 11:30 PM to 3:00 AM last Friday night.
这就是妳的口供吗？
Is that the statement you made?
- 对，先生　- 那是真的吗？
- Yes, sir.  - Was it the truth?
年轻女士，妳回答前思考清楚，除非妳想去坐牢
You better think before you answer, young lady, unless you wanna go to jail.
坐牢？
Jail?
为了包庇罪犯而提供虚假的不在场证明，那就要坐牢
For setting up a false alibi to keep another from being punished for a crime.
- 埃默瑞克先生不会犯罪　- 他会犯罪而且已经做了
- Mr. Emmerich wouldn't commit a crime.  - He would and did.
- 告诉他真相　- 朗大叔
- Tell him the truth.  - Uncle Lon.
这是妳唯一能做的事，除非妳想因妨碍司法而被起诉
It's the only thing to do, unless you want to be indicted for obstructing justice.
我昨天说的…
What I said yesterday was...
并非完全…我的意思是…
Well, it wasn't exactly... I mean...
- 那不是…　- 是事实吗？
- It wasn't really the...  - Was it the truth?
不是，先生
No, sir.
- 妳没有和埃默瑞克在一起，对吗？　- 对，先生
- You weren't with Emmerich, were you?  - No, sir.
- 妳在别的地方，而且没和他在一起　- 对，先生
- You were someplace else and you were not with him.  - Yes, sir.
是他告诉妳该说什么，让妳记在心里
He told you what to say, made you learn it by heart.
- 回答我　- 不
- Answer me.  - No.
我的意思是，对，先生
I mean, yes, sir.
我的意思是，我记在心里！
I mean, I learned it by heart!
- 给她重新录口供，让她在上面签字　- 是，长官
- Get a new statement from her. Have her sign it.  - Yes, sir.
年轻女士，这次我要全部的真相
This time, young lady, I want the whole truth.
小姐，到这边来
Over here, miss.
朗大叔，对不起
I'm sorry, Uncle Lon.
我尽力了
I tried.
对妳而言，已经做得很好了
You did pretty well, considering.
朗大叔，我的旅行怎么办？我还能去吗？
What about my trip, Uncle Lon? Is it still on?
宝贝，别担心，妳会有很多旅行的
Don't worry, baby. You'll have plenty of trips.
埃默瑞克，看来一切都结束了
Seems to be all wrapped up, Emmerich.
还给你
Oh, here.
如果你不介意，我想打电话给我的妻子
Say, I'd like to, uh, telephone my wife, if you don't mind.
- 太晚了，她可能会担心　- 你请便
- Getting late. She might be worried.  - Help yourself.
但别想逃跑，你逃不远的
But don't try to run. You won't get very far.
（亲爱的梅，请原谅我…
我无法面对我所对妳做的事，我…）
埃默瑞克！
Emmerich!
- 等等！住手！救命！　- 过来！
- Wait! Stop! Look out!  - Come on!
- 你等着瞧！　- 松手！
- You wait and see!  - Break loose!
你等着瞧，肮脏的告密者！
You wait and see, you dirty fink!
你会和你的哥们儿埃默瑞克落得同样下场！
You're gonna wind up where your pal Emmerich is!
你会躺进停尸房！你等着瞧，肮脏的告密者！
You're gonna wind up in the morgue! You wait and see, you dirty fink!
- 关他进去！　- 告密者！该死的告密者！
- Haul him in!  - Fink! Fink! Fink!
去守住防火通道
Fire escape.
我们找路易·查维利
We're looking for Louis Ciavelli.
[ 玛利亚说意大利语祈祷 ]
[ Maria praying in Italian ]
如果你们不坚持进来的话，我会很感激
I'd consider it a great favor if you didn't insist on going in.
查维利夫人正在…我不说你们也看得出来
Mrs. Ciavelli is... Well, I don't have to tell you.
威廉，如果神父说可以，那就可以
If the father says it's okay, Williams, it's okay.
- 给局长办公室打电话　- 是，长官
- Call the commissioner's office.  - Yes, sir.
局长认识我，提我的名字，索提诺
The commissioner knows me. Mention my name. Sortino.
谢谢你，神父
Thank you, Father.
（埃默瑞克律师开枪自杀）
「埃默瑞克毕业于州立法律大学」
"Emmerich was a graduate of the law college of State University
「并在这里工作超过二十五年」
and had practiced here for over 25 years."
多么愚蠢，难以置信
What foolishness. Unbelievable.
- 他最多被判刑两年　- 他甚至背叛了他自己
- He wouldn't have gotten more than two years.  - He even double-crossed himself.
- 博士，你的头怎么样？　- 完好如初，没什么事
- How's your head, Doc?  - Good as it ever was, which isn't saying much.
到处都在传播你的照片，出城对你来说并不容易
Getting out of town won't be a cinch for you with your picture spread around.
我会出去的，没问题
Oh, I'll get out, all right.
我会打辆出租车到城市郊区
I'll take a taxi to the edge of town
然后让司机载我去克利夫兰市
and have him drive me as far as Cleveland.
迪克斯，你确定不跟我一起走吗？
Sure you wouldn't come along with me, Dix?
留着吧
Keep it.
不用了，谢谢
No, thank you.
如果你不来，你能资助我吗？
If you won't come, will you finance me?
我手里只有四、五美元了
I haven't got but four or five dollars.
我当然可以资助你，你需要多少？
Sure, I'll finance you. How much you need?
我有一千美元就够了，非常感谢
I can get along on a thousand dollars, thanks very much.
剩下的宝石留给你，价值五万美元呢
And you can have the rest of these stones. That's $50,000 worth.
我拿着宝石有什么用？难道我会走进当铺卖掉它们吗？
What would I do? Can you see me walking into a hock shop with that stuff?
首先他们会认为这是膺品，然后他们就会呼叫防暴警队
First they'd think they were phony, and then they'd yell for the riot squad.
不，博士，我可以给你一千块钱，但不用给我宝石
No, Doc, you can have the thousand, but no rocks for me.
好吧，谢谢你，迪克斯
Well, thank you, Dix.
告诉我写信到哪里，至少我可以把五千块钱尾款寄给你
Tell me where to write you. At least I can send you the five grand you got coming.
- 你在肯塔基州的地址是什么？　- 算了
- What will your address be in Kentucky?  - Forget it.
也许我还会见到你
Maybe I'll see you around.
好吧…
Well...
- 那么再见了　- 再见，博士
- Good-bye then.  - Good-bye, Doc.
等等，你还没有武器
Hey, wait a minute. You haven't got a heater.
你可以拿我的，但是…朵儿，妳有枪吗？
I'd let you have mine, but... You got a gun, Doll?
没有，迪克斯，我以前有一支，但我猜有人把它偷走了
No, Dix. I used to have one around, but I guess somebody stole it.
我不想要枪，自从二十岁起我就不带枪了
I don't want a gun. Thank you. I haven't carried a gun since my 20s.
你带着枪，你就会射杀警察，这是坏习惯，很难改变
You carry a gun, you shoot a policeman. Bad rap, hard to beat.
你不带枪，警察拿枪指着你时，你干脆投降
You don't carry a gun, you give up when they hold one on you.
好吧，博士，你最了解
All right, Doc. You know best.
亲爱的，来杯咖啡如何？
How about a cup of coffee, honey?
这个德国小老头真有趣，我完全搞不懂他
That squarehead. He's a funny little guy. I don't get him at all.
也许因为他是外国人，思维方式和我们不一样
Maybe it's because he's a foreigner. They just don't think like us.
我也必须在天亮之前离开城市
I gotta get out of town too and before morning.
总之，他有足够的胆量
Anyway, he's got plenty of guts.
- 亲爱的，来杯咖啡如何？　- 要么快弄，要么闭嘴
- How about a cup of coffee, honey?  - Make it or shut up about it.
- 伤口裂开了　- 聪明姑娘
- It's that wound.  - Bright girl.
迪克斯，伤口又开始流血了，我有止疼药
Dix, it's starting to bleed again. I know, aspirin.
皮克林大道和中央大街
Pickering Avenue and Center Street.
- 你知道在哪里吗？　- 城市的另一头
- You know where that is?  - Other side of town.
- 有多远？　- 我能在一小时内赶过去
- How far is that?  - I can make it in an hour.
很好，我有亲戚住在那里
Okay. I got relatives living there.
我要换乘火车，没事可做
I'm between trains and I got nothing else to do.
我了解，我在城市两头都有亲戚
I know how it is. I got relatives myself,
（弗兰克·舒尔茨 [ 德国姓氏 ] ）
总写信找我要钱
on both sides. Always writing me letters for money.
[ 双方说德语 ]
[ Speaking German ]
我很久没讲德语了
I haven't spoken German for a long, long time.
- 你有慕尼黑口音　- [ 德语 ] 当然，我出生于慕尼黑
- You have a München accent.  - Natürlich. I was born there.
但你知道人们怎么说的：「有钱的地方就是家」
But you know what they say. "Home is where the money is."
[ 德语 ] 对
Ja.
弗朗茨，你愿意载我去克利夫兰市吗？
Franz, how would you like to drive me to Cleveland?
那是很远的路，朋友
It's a long way, my friend.
但还是比明早坐火车要快吧
But it would be quicker than to take the train tomorrow morning.
- 那你亲戚怎么办？　- 忘掉他们吧
- What about your relatives?  - Ah, forget them.
我不知道，克利夫兰市非常远
Well, I don't know. Cleveland. That's a long way.
- 要花很多钱　- 先给你五十美元小费，你说如何？
- Costs a lot of money.  - There's a $50 tip for you. What do you say?
为了五十美元，我愿意载你去北极
For $50, I'd drive you to the North Pole.
如果我们要去克利夫兰市，最好加满油
Well, we better get gas if we're going to Cleveland.
我们出城后再停车，然后我们就能一次性把事情做完
Let's not stop till we get out of town. Then we can do everything at once.
吃晚餐，喝啤酒，抽雪茄，舒服地休息一下
Have a little meal, beer, a cigar and go in comfort.
看来你是一个很懂得享乐的人
I can see you're a man who likes his pleasures.
弗朗茨，我问你，生命中除了享乐还能干嘛？
Well, Franz, what else is there in life, I ask you?
[ 德语 ] 请
Bitte.
妳已经出去了两小时，发生了什么？
You've been gone nearly two hours. What happened?
很花时间，我被巡逻警车拦住两次
It took time. I was stopped twice. Prowl cars.
附近都是臭警察，你无法想象…
The neighborhood's crawling with coppers. You can't imagine --
- 妳弄到车了吗？　- 是的
- All right. Did you get a car?  - Yes.
这是零钱，只花了四百美元，我从大维维安那里买的
Here's the change. It only came to $400. I got it from Big Vivian.
车况还很好，除了刹车片需要更换…
It's in good shape, except the brakes need relining --
- 妳加油了吗？　- 加了
- Did you put gas in it?  - Yes.
- 停在哪里？　- 三个街区外
- Where'd you park it?  - Three blocks away.
- 做得好　- 迪克斯
- Good girl.  - Dix.
- 什么事？　- 我很害怕
- Yeah?  - I'm-I'm scared.
- 外面都是警察　- 我一点也不担心他们
- All those cops out there.  - They don't worry me one little bit.
我会慢慢驾驶，沿着主大道一直开
I'll drive slow. Head right down the main boulevard,
十小时之后，我就会回到老家
and in 10 hours, I'll be home.
- 亲爱的，你如何驾驶那么长的路？　- 我可以做到
- Dix, honey, how you gonna drive all that way?  - I'll make it.
不行，你现在的状态根本不行
No. Not in the shape you're in. Not in a million years.
- 我可以做到　- 迪克斯
- I'll make it.  - Dix.
让我跟你一起走吧？
Let me go with you?
- 迪克斯，求你了　- 妳疯了吗？
- Please, Dix. Please.  - Are you crazy?
我在逃亡，我正被重金悬赏
I'm on the lam. I'm wanted bad, packing heat.
- 妳跟着能做什么？　- 我可以开车
- What good would you be?  - I could drive.
不行，朵儿，我犯的是谋杀案，妳知道那是什么意思
No, Doll. I'm wanted on a killing rap. You know what that means.
我不在乎，我只想和你在一起
I don't care. I want to be with you.
你不能丢下我走，我不让你走
You can't go without me. I won't let you.
我不告诉你车在哪里
I won't tell you where the car is.
我不明白
I don't get it.
我真不明白
I just don't get it.
好吧，收拾妳的东西
All right. Get your things packed.
我们再多点播几张唱片
Come on. Let's play some more.
珍妮，我没有硬币了，瑞德，你呢？
I'm fresh out of nickels, Jeannie. How about you, Red?
- 我一直没有　- 去弄些来
- I'm always fresh out.  - Well, get some.
妳挺能花男生钱的
You know, you can cost a guy a lot of dough.
他花个硬币还抱怨，真小气
Nickels he's complaining about. What a spender.
当然，他想要约会，他总是想要约会
Sure, he wants a date. He always wants a date.
而我们去哪里？去看放过三遍的电影
And where do we go? To a third-run movie.
然后开车兜风，再爆掉两个轮胎
Then we take a ride and blow two tires.
接着我们来到这里，你为我点了什么？可乐
Then we come here, and what do you treat me to? Cokes.
我甚至无法听唱片
I can't even listen to records.
- 这是给你的　- 谢谢
- That's for you.  - Thanks.
- 请你把这些钱换成硬币　- 当然
- Would you have change for this in nickels, please?  - Sure thing.
你至少应该弄到足够的硬币来为我点播音乐
At least dig down for enough to play me some music.
嗷，珍妮，别说了
Aw, Jeannie, cut it out.
小伙子们，打扰一下
Excuse me, boys.
年轻女士，我也喜欢音乐
Young lady, I like music too.
- 妳可以为我点播一首吗？　- 当然，你想听什么？
- Would you play me a tune?  - Sure. What do you want me to play?
- 妳随便点　- 天啊，你这里有多少硬币？
- You pick 'em.  - Gosh, how many have you got here?
- 不是很多，点播妳喜欢的任何音乐　- 好的
- Not very many. Play what you like.  - Okay.
先生
Mister.
先生，已经很晚了
Mister, it's getting late.
先生，我们该走了
Mister, we better be moving along.
还有时间，朋友，还有时间
Plenty of time, my friend. Plenty of time.
先生，去克利夫兰市的路非常远
Look, mister, it's a long way to Cleveland.
嗯，我猜我们最好现在就走
Well, I suppose we better go now.
别走，我们还没用完所有硬币
Don't go. We haven't used all the nickels.
- 妳用吧　- 谢谢，你真是太好了
- You use 'em.  - Thanks. It's sure nice of you.
- 不值一提　- 再见，谢谢，非常感谢
- Don't mention it.  - Good-bye, and thanks. Thanks ever so much.
这是我的荣幸
Pleasure was all mine.
你们要干什么？
You men want something?
艾德，你认为呢？
What do you think, Ed?
可能是头号嫌疑犯
Might be the number one boy.
- 只是可能　- 这是怎么回事？
- Just might be.  - See, what is this?
- 闭嘴　- 最好搜他的身
- Shut up.  - Better frisk him.
- 请便　- 举起双手
- Go right ahead.  - Put up your hands.
你一定是把我和别人弄混了
You must have me mixed up with somebody else.
我来自克利夫兰市，做进口生意，我名叫克莱珀
I'm from Cleveland. The importing business. My name's Klemper.
什么也没有，出租车司机，让我看看那外套
Nothing there. Let me see that coat, hackie.
- 你犯了一个大…　- 闭嘴，别管闲事
- You're making a big --  - Shut up and keep out of this.
比尔，你最好打电话给城里核实一下
Tell you what, Bill. Better phone the city and check on the description.
没必要核实了，我会跟城里说我们抓住他了
We don't need a description. I'll tell 'em we got him.
- 先生，把双手举起来　- 当然
- Okay, mister. Keep those hands up.  - Of course.
警官，打扰一下，你能告诉我一些事吗？
Excuse me, Officer, but will you tell me something?
也许吧，脸朝着前方
Maybe. Just keep your face front.
你们来这里多长时间了？
How long have you been out here?
- 这问题真有趣　- 它并不重要
- That's a darn funny question.  - It's not important.
我们通过那扇窗户观察了你两、三分钟
We've been watching you through that window two, three minutes.
是的，大概正是点播一首唱片的时间
Ah, yes. Say about as long as it takes to play a phonograph record.
什么意思？你在说什么？
How's that again? What are you talking about?
- 没什么　- 脸朝着前方
- It doesn't matter.  - Keep your face front.
我可以抽雪茄吗？
Do you mind if I smoke a cigar?
老实站在这里，先生，抽雪茄的事稍后再说
Just stand quiet there, mister. We'll talk about smoking a cigar later.
当然，警官，当然
Certainly, Officer. Certainly.
（火车轨道，交叉口）
迪克斯，你现在感觉如何？
How you feeling now, Dix?
还好，有点冷，往年的这个时候没这么冷
All right. Cold. Didn't used to get cold this time of year.
亲爱的，你为什么不让我开一会儿呢？
Why don't you let me drive for a while, honey.
妳不认识路，我不想总给妳指路
You don't know the way. I'd only have to keep telling you.
还很远…
Much longer, Di --
迪克斯？迪克斯？
Dix? Dix?
迪克斯
Dix.
不，迪克斯
No, Dix. Dix.
先生，先生，先生！
Mister. Mister. Mister!
先生，请帮帮我，我要找医生
Mister, you gotta help me. I gotta find a doctor.
- 我丈夫生病了　- 好的，我指给妳看
- My husband, he's sick.  - Come on. I'll show you.
向前直走，夫人，一直到街区的尽头
Go straight on, ma'am. Down to the end of the block.
我们可以找到斯旺森大夫，他就住在榆树街附近
We'll get Doc Swanson. He lives right near here on Elm Street.
我丈夫，他生病晕倒了
My husband, he's sick, fainted.
扶他进去，我给他做检查，就在旁边这房间
Get him inside where I can look at him. Right in this other room here, please.
抬到桌上
Up on the table.
脱掉他的外套
Take his coat off.
放到椅子上
Put it on the chair.
他正在出血，他失血过多，发生了什么？
This man's been hemorrhaging. He's lost a lot of blood. What happened?
他受伤了，在一场车祸中受的伤
He was hurt. He was hurt in an auto accident.
- 他受伤多长时间？　- 几天了
- How long has this wound been let go?  - A couple of days.
医生，严重吗？他伤得很严重吗？
Is it bad, Doctor? Is he hurt real bad?
情况不好
Well, it's not good.
- 艾金森先生，你胳膊有劲吗？　- 我猜有劲，大夫
- You got a strong arm, Mr. Atkinson?  - Good as any, Doc, I guess.
到这边来，请帮我拿着这个
Come around here and hold this for me, please.
好的
That's right.
这就行了
There we are.
喂，让汤姆接电话，我是斯旺森医生
Hello, uh, let me talk to Tom. This is Dr. Swanson.
把他叫醒
Wake him up.
- 我口渴，倒点水给我喝　- 好的，迪克斯
- I'm thirsty. Get me a drink of water.  - Sure, Dix. Sure.
躺下，甜心，请躺下
Lie down, sweetheart. Please lie down.
喂，是汤姆治安官吗？听着
Hello, Sheriff? Listen, Tom.
我这里有一个男人，身上有枪伤，非常严重
I got a man here with a gunshot wound. Pretty bad.
- 甜心，喝水　- 那是谁？
- Here, sweetheart.  - Who's that?
我必须带你看医生，迪克斯，我没办法
I had to take you to the doctor's, Dix. I couldn't help it.
扣住他？没必要，他现在不省人事
Hold him? I don't have to. The man's unconscious.
不，我不认识他
No, no, no. He's a stranger to me.
他妻子和他在一起，她说是一场车祸
His wife's with him. She says it was an auto accident.
迪克斯
Dix.
迪克斯，迪克斯！
Dix. Dix!
迪克斯，迪克斯
Dix. Dix. Dix.
他肯定走不远的
Well, he won't get very far, that's for sure.
他身体里剩下的血都不够支撑一只小鸡活命
He hasn't got enough blood left in him to keep a chicken alive.
- 还有问题吗？　- 我不喜欢纠缠在同一个问题上
- Any more questions?  - I don't like to harp on the same point,
但迪崔克会怎样？如果这个警察部门过去…
but what about Ditrich? If the past of this police department --
迪崔克在牢房里，他将接受审判
Ditrich's in jail. He'll go to trial.
他将被十二个他曾为之服务的陪审团公民审判
He'll be tried by 12 citizens for whom he's been working.
让他们决定该对迪崔克严惩不贷还是从轻发落
Let them show justice or compassion as they see fit.
局长，那你的裁决是什么？
What would be your verdict, Commissioner?
我不确定，我完全不确定
I'm not sure. I'm not sure at all.
我这样说吧
Let me put it this way.
警察部门有腐败官员，这并不奇怪
It's not anything strange that there are corrupt officers in police departments.
警察们试图清除的罪恶会感染某些人，但不是所有人
The dirt they're trying to clean up is bound to rub off on some, but not all.
也许一百个人中有一个败类，但另外九十九个都是正直的人
Maybe one out of 100. The other 99 are honest men trying to do an honest job.
- 斯考利大街１９３号发生抢劫　- 听听
- Robbery at 193 Scully Avenue.  - Listen.
各单位注意，发生抢劫…
All units, robbery at 193 --
两个白人男子，持蓝钢手枪…
...two male Caucasians armed with blue steel --
我知道你们警务记者整天都听到这些案件
I know you're police reporters and hear this all day long,
但请用你们的良心去听，而不只是用耳朵
but listen with your conscience, not just your ears.
戴一顶棕色毡帽…
...wearing a brown felt hat --
詹姆斯大道２５号发生枪击，女人在尖叫
...a shooting at 25 James Boulevard. Woman screaming.
１２号警车，詹姆斯大道２５号发生枪击，女人…
Car 1-2, shooting at 2-5 James Boulevard. Woman --
各单位注意，强火力枪战，在滨河路３２１６号…
All units, strong-arm slugging, 3216 River Drive --
每一次呼叫，我们都要派出警察支援
We send police assistance to every one of those calls,
因为它们不只是电台里的代号，它们是求救的声音
because they're not just codes numbers on a radio beam, they're cries for help.
人们被诈骗、抢劫、谋杀、强奸
People are being cheated, robbed, murdered, raped.
一年三百六十五天，一天二十四小时，每时每刻都在发生
And that goes on 24 hours a day, every day in the year.
犯罪活动并不罕见，它们经常发生
And that's not exceptional, that's usual.
现代世界的每个城市都是这样
It's the same in every city of the modern world.
但假设我们没有警察，不论好坏
But suppose we had no police force, good or bad.
假设我们…
Suppose we had...
只是沉默
just silence.
没人收听，没人回答
Nobody to listen. Nobody to answer.
战斗结束，丛林法则获胜
The battle's finished. The jungle wins.
肉食野兽占据统治地位，各位试想一下
The predatory beasts take over. Think about it.
先生们
Well, gentlemen,
三个男人进了监狱，三个男人死了，其中一个是自杀
three men are in jail, three men dead, one by his own hand.
还有一个男人在逃亡，而且我们相信他伤得很重
One man's a fugitive, and we have reason to believe seriously wounded.
七个男人抓住了六个，这不错
That's six out of seven. Not bad.
我们也会抓住最后一个
We'll get the last one too.
某种程度上，他是所有人之中最危险的一个
In some ways, he's the most dangerous of them all.
一个冷酷杀手，一个恶棍
A hardened killer. A hooligan.
没有人类情感，没有怜悯之心
A man without human feeling or human mercy.
我告诉妳…
I tell ya...
那匹黑马是我们在山核桃木农场最好的一匹
the black one's the best we ever had at Hickorywood.
那匹枣色的马也不错，但…黑色的是上等雄马驹
The bay's all right, but... the black's a real good colt.
我们最漂亮的马…
Prettiest we have -- goin' --
那匹马是…爸养过最好的
anything... Pa ever bred.
最容易养，而且…它总跑在前面…
Easiest thing, yeah, but... he's always... way out front of...
比其余小马驹都快
the other yearlings.
它是我所见过…最棒的一匹赛马
He's a stake horse or... I never saw one.
我真希望…
I sure hope...
爸没有卖掉它
Pa don't sell him.
如果爸留住那匹黑色雄马驹，一切都会很好
If Pa just hangs on to that black colt, everything's gonna be all right.
噢，天呐
Oh, dear God.
我说过了，我再说一遍
I said it. I'll say it again.
如果爸留住那匹黑色雄马驹
If Pa just hangs on to that black colt,
一切…都会很好
everything's... gonna be okay.
这是什么…
What's this --
（山核桃木农场）
噢，迪克斯！迪克斯
Oh, Dix! Dix.
迪克斯，迪克斯？
Dix. Dix?
噢，天呐，噢，我的天呐
Oh, God. Oh, my God.
迪克斯，迪克斯？
Dix. Dix?
（剧终）
（米高梅影业摄制于美国好莱坞）
（演出名单）